华 纳 兄 弟 影 业     出 品
艾 文 · 温 克 勒     制 片 作 品
马 丁 · 斯 科 塞 斯     电 影 作 品
领 衔 主 演:  罗 伯 特 · 德 尼 罗
领 衔 主 演:  雷 · 利 奥 塔
领 衔 主 演:  乔 · 佩 西
领 衔 主 演:  洛 兰 · 布 蕾 科
领 衔 主 演:  保 罗 · 索 维 诺
本 片 改 编 自 真 实 故 事
纽约  1970年
什么声音
What the fuck is that?
吉米
Jimmy?
- 什么事  - 我是不是撞到什么了
- What's up? - Did I hit something?
到底是什么
What the fuck is that?
是不是爆胎啦
Maybe you got a flat?
不是啦
No.
他妈的  最好停下来看看
What the fuck? You better pull over and see.
他还活着  你他妈的真是人渣
He's still alive. You fucking piece of shit!
去死吧  婊子养的  看着我
Die, you motherfucker! Look at me!
从我有记忆开始  我就想成为黑帮分子
As far back as I can remember, I always wanted to be a gangster.
盗 亦 有 道
监 制:  芭 芭 拉 · 德 菲 纳
本 片 改 编 自 尼 古 拉 斯 · 派 勒 吉 所 著 ‘黑 帮 兄 弟’ 一 书
编 剧
尼 古 拉 斯 · 派 勒 吉 & 马 丁 · 斯 科 塞 斯
制 片:  艾 文 · 温 克 勒
导 演:  马 丁 · 斯 科 塞 斯
对我来说
To me,
成为黑帮分子比当选美国总统还好
being a gangster was better than being president of the United States.
纽约东区  布鲁克林  1955年
在我去计程车站找零工之前
Even before I first wandered into the cabstand for an after-school job...
我就知道我要成为他们的一份子
I knew I wanted to be a part of them.
我有种归属感
It was there that I knew I belonged.
对我来说是一种成就感  在一个充满了无名小卒的环境中
To me, it meant being somebody in a neighborhood full of nobodies.
他们不像别人  他们能随心所欲
They weren't like anybody else. They did whatever they wanted.
他们在消防栓前面停车而从来也不会被开罚单
They double-parked in front of a hydrant, nobody ever gave them a ticket.
夏天通宵赌扑克
In the summer, when they played cards all night...
也没人敢叫警察
nobody ever called the cops.
东尼·史达斯  你好吗
Tony Stacks. How are you?
杜迪·西席罗
Tuddy Cicero.
这就是加拿希小子吗
Could this be the Canarsie Kid?
- 你好吗  - 蛮好的
- How are you? - Good.
杜迪
Tuddy.
杜迪的大哥保利是整个社区的大老板
Tuddy ran the cabstand and the Bella Vista Pizzeria...
他替他打理计程车站和贝拉维斯塔披萨屋等地点
and other places for his brother, Paul, who was the boss of the neighborhood.
保利看起来动作很慢
Paulie might have moved slow...
那是因为保利不需要为任何人做事
but it was only because Paulie didn't have to move for anybody.
- 都是你不好  - 是你先开始的
- It's your fault. - You started it.
我先开始的  是你不好
I started it? It's your fault.
起先我父母都很高兴我在对街找到一份工作
At first my parents loved that I found a job across the street from the house.
我父亲是爱尔兰人  他十一岁就被送去工作了
My father, who was Irish, was sent to work at the age of 11.
他很高兴我找到工作
He liked that I got myself a job.
他常说美国孩子都被惯坏了
He always used to say that American kids were spoiled lazy.
- 爸  再见  - 再见
- Bye, Dad. - Bye.
再见  米奇
See you, Mikey.
再见  亨利
Bye, Henry.
亨利  过马路要小心呀
Henry! Watch how you cross!
记得带牛奶回来
Bring back milk!
我妈妈也高兴呀  当她知道西席罗家
My mother was happy after she found out that the Ciceros...
和她是从西西里同一个地区出来的  对我妈妈而言
came from the same part of Sicily as she did. To my mother...
就像她的祷告都应验了
that was the answer to all her prayers.
我是世上最幸运的小孩
I was the luckiest kid in the world.
我可以到任何地方  做任何事
I could go anywhere, I could do anything.
我认识每一个人  大家也都认识我
I knew everybody, and everybody knew me.
兄弟们开车来  杜迪就让我
Wiseguys would pull up and Tuddy would toss me their keys...
帮他们停凯迪拉克车
and let me park their Cadillacs.
那时候我还是个小鬼
Here I am, this little kid,
坐在方向盘后面  连路都看不见
I can't even see over the steering wheel...
就能停凯迪拉克了
and I'm parking Cadillacs.
可是  没多久
But it wasn't too long...
我父母就反对我在计程车站的工作了
before my parents changed their minds about my job at the cabstand.
给你妈妈跟妹妹
For your mother and sister.
对他们来说  计程站的工作只是零工  对我
For them, the cabstand was supposed to be a part-time job. But for me...
却是全天候
it was definitely full-time.
我唯一想做的事
That's all I wanted to do.
像我爸爸这种人永远也不会了解  我是其中的一份子
People like my father could never understand, but I was a part of something.
我有所属  他们以成人待我
I belonged. I was treated like a grown-up.
告诉他519
Tell him 519.
每天我都在学些有用的技巧
Every day I was learning to score.
这里一块钱  那里一块钱
A dollar here, a dollar there.
我好像活在梦幻里
I was living in a fantasy.
今天在学校还顺利吗
Did you have a good day at school?
父亲总是非常生气
My father was always pissed off.
他气自己赚钱太少
Pissed that he made such lousy money...
他气弟弟米奇活在轮椅上
pissed that my kid brother Michael was in a wheelchair.
他气我们一家七口挤在一间小房子里
He was pissed that there were seven of us living in such a tiny house.
你跟我说说这个
Tell me about this.
是学校来的信
It's a letter from school.
信上说你已经几个月没上学了
It says you haven't been there in months.
几个月了
In months!
你是个没用的混球
You're a bum!
你长大想做个流浪汉吗
Want to grow up to be a bum?
过了一阵子之后  他气我整天泡在计程车站
After a while, he was mostly pissed because I hung around the cabstand.
他知道站里有些什么勾当
He knew what went on at that cabstand.
我经常挨揍  可是我已经不在乎了
Every once in a while, I'd have to take a beating. But by then, I didn't care.
就我看来
The way I saw it...
每个人都有挨揍的时候
everybody takes a beating sometime.
- 我不能再送货了  - 什么  你这样会把所有事都搞砸
- I can't make any more deliveries. - What? You'll fuck everything up.
我老爸说他会杀了我  你看
My dad says he'll kill me. Look.
跟我来
Come on with me.
- 那是送信到你家的邮差吗  - 不是
- Is that him, kid? - No.
- 那一个呢  - 也不是
- How about him? - No.
- 那个就是  - 去找他
- That's the guy. - Get him.
抱歉
Excuse me.
- 人渣  - 你这块狗屎  给我过来
- Scumbag. - Come here, you piece of shit.
- 认识这个小鬼吗  - 认得呀
- Know this kid? - Yeah.
- 你知道他住哪里吗  - 知道
- Know where he lives? - Yeah.
- 这家的信是由你送的吗  - 是的
- You deliver mail to his house? - Yeah.
从现在起  任何从学校寄给他家的信都给我
From now on, any letter from that school to his house comes directly here.
- 你懂吗  - 懂
- Understand? - Yeah.
假如再有一封学校的信送进那小鬼家里的话
Another letter from that school goes to that kid's house...
你会被塞进烤披萨的炉子里
in the fucking oven you'll go, head first.
就这样  再也没有缺课的来信  再也没有学校的来信
That was it. No more letters from truant officers. No letters from school.
其实  任何信件都没有了
In fact, no more letters from anybody.
最后  经过几星期  我妈妈去邮局抱怨了
Finally after a few weeks, my mother went to the post office to complain.
从那以后  我怎么能回到学校去发誓效忠国旗
How could I go to school after that...
我又怎能坐在那里听政府如何好的屁话呢
and pledge allegiance to the flag and sit through good government bullshit?
保利最恨电话了  他不肯在家里装电话
Paulie hated phones. He wouldn't have one in his house.
米奇打来了  要不要我回他电话
Mickey called. Want me to call him back?
好吧  打过去
All right, make the call.
他的电话都是由别人传达给他
He got all his calls second hand. Then you'd have to call the people back...
然后手下再从公用电话回电
from an outside phone.
你有没有五分钱  帮我打个电话给他
Got a nickel? Get him on the phone.
有几个混混整天就是忙着帮保利接电话
There were guys, that's all they did all day, was take care of Paulie's calls.
对一个整天忙碌不停的人来说  他很少跟人说话
For a guy who moved all day long, Paulie didn't talk to six people.
假如工会有了问题或彩票上有争议
If there was a union problem or, say, a beef in the numbers...
只有高级干部可以跟保利商议
only the top guys could meet with Paulie to discuss the problem.
保利讨厌开会  凡事都是一对一解决
Everything was one-on-one. Paulie hated conferences.
他不要别人听到他说的话
He didn't want anybody hearing what he said...
或听到别人说给他听的话
and he didn't want anybody listening to what he was being told.
好几百人以保利当靠山  他们所赚的都给保利一份
Hundreds of guys depended on Paulie, he got a piece of everything they made.
那就是保护费  就像在西西里  只不过这是美国
It was a tribute, like in the old country, except they were doing it in America.
保利也只不过保护他们不被别人欺侮诈骗
All they got from Paulie was protection from other guys looking to rip them off.
就是这样  FBI始终搞不懂这一点
That's what it's all about. That's what the FBI could never understand.
保利所做的
What Paulie and the Organization does...
就是保护那些无法受警察保护的人
is offer protection for people who can't go to the cops. That's it.
保利就像是兄弟们的警察局长
That's all it is. They're like the police department for wiseguys.
别人看我的眼光都不一样  因为我和大人物在一起
People looked at me differently, and they knew I was with somebody.
我连礼拜天买新鲜面包都用不着排队了
I didn't have to wait in line at the bakery on Sunday mornings for fresh bread.
老板知道我跟谁在一起
The owner knew who I was with...
他会从柜台后面走出来  不管有多少人在等
and he'd come from around the counter. No matter how many were waiting...
他都会先招呼我
I was taken care of first.
邻居再也不将车停在我们车道上了
Our neighbors didn't park in our driveway anymore...
虽然我们没有车  我十三岁的时候
even though we didn't have a car. At 13...
我赚的钱已经比附近的大人还多
I was making more money than most of the grown-ups around.
我的钱多得花不完  要什么有什么
I had more money than I could spend. I had it all.
有一天  附近几个孩子们还帮我妈把菜拎回家
One day, some neighborhood kids carried my mother's groceries all the way home.
知道为什么吗
You know why?
因为他们尊敬我
It was out of respect.
妈妈  你认为如何
Hi, Mom, what do you think?
- 你看我的鞋  很棒吧  - 老天呀
- Look at my shoes, aren't they great? - My God.
你看上去像个黑帮分子
You look like a gangster.
他们射中我了  救命
They shot me. Help!
亨利  把门关上
Henry, shut the door.
那是我第一次看到枪击
That was the first time I had ever seen anyone shot.
别在店里搞这些  天呐
Can't have that in here. Jesus Christ!
我不准在这里弄这种事
I can't have that in this joint.
我记得我为那个人感到难过
I remember feeling bad about the guy...
我也记得或许杜迪是对的
but I also remember feeling that maybe Tuddy was right.
我知道保利不要有任何人死在屋里
I knew Paulie didn't want anybody dying in the building.
你真是个大白痴  你糟蹋了八条围裙
You're a real jerk. You wasted eight fucking aprons on this guy.
你他妈的到底怎么了  我要让这个小鬼长进一点
What the hell's wrong with you? I got to toughen this kid up.
那真是一段光彩的日子
It was a glorious time.
到处都是兄弟们
And wiseguys were all over the place.
那是在阿帕拉钦事件之前
It was before Apalachin and before Crazy Joe...
在疯子周和老大开战前
decided to take on a boss and start a war.
我就是那时候认清世界
It was when I met the world.
并认识吉米·康威
And it was when I first met Jimmy Conway.
他顶多不过二十八九岁
He couldn't have been more than 28 or 29 at the time...
但已经是个传奇人物了
but he was already a legend.
他只要一走进来  厅里所有的人就像发疯一样
He'd walk in the door and everybody who worked the room just went wild.
帮他开门  就给一百块小费
He'd give the doorman $100 just for opening the door.
他常塞百元大钞给那些发牌跟主持赌局的人
He'd give hundreds to the dealers and the guys who ran the games.
连酒保也有百元小费  只要冰块够冰的话
The bartender got $100 just for keeping the ice cubes cold.
让爱尔兰人来赢你们这些意大利人的钱了
The Irishman is here to take all you guineas' money.
- 你要不要喝一杯  - 给我一杯七喜加海马七威士忌
- Want a drink? - Give me a 7 and 7.
- 来见见这个小子亨利  - 很高兴认识你
- I'd like you to meet the kid Henry. - How you doing?
- 谢谢你  - 继续上酒
- Thank you. - Keep them coming.
吉米是全城当时最令人敬畏的人之一
Jimmy was one of the most feared guys in the city.
他第一次被关起来时才十一岁
He was first locked up at 11...
十六岁就替他老板杀人了
and he was doing hits for mob bosses when he was 16.
吉米一点也不在乎杀人  那是他的职业
See, hits never bothered Jimmy. It was business.
但是吉米真正的爱好
But what Jimmy really loved to do...
是偷东西
what he really loved to do was steal.
那对他来说是一种享受
He actually enjoyed it.
吉米就是那种支持电影里的坏蛋的那种人
Jimmy was the kind of guy who rooted for the bad guys in the movies.
把你的钱包给我
Give me your wallet.
你也许知道我们是谁  我们可清楚的知道你的底细  懂吗
You might know who we are, but we know who you are. Understand?
他是当时城里最大的劫车犯之一
He was one of the city's biggest hijackers...
劫运酒车  运烟车  运虾  刮胡刀  龙虾等等
of booze, cigarettes, razor blades, shrimp and lobsters.
虾跟龙虾是最好的货  很快就销出去了
Shrimp and lobsters were best. They went really fast.
几乎所有的劫案都是不用暴力的
Almost all of them were gimmies. They just gave it up, no problem.
他们甚至称他为绅士吉米
They called him Jimmy the Gent.
帮帮小姐
Help the lady.
开货车的都喜欢他  有好货的时候
Drivers loved him. They used to tip him off...
他们都会把消息告诉他  当然  每个人都得到好处
about the really good loads. Of course, everybody got a piece.
谢了  我等下再来拿剩下的烟
Thanks, I'll be back for the rest later.
好吧  一会儿见
Okay, see you later.
亨利  到这里来
Henry, come here.
- 跟汤米打个招呼  - 你好吗  亨利
- Say hello to Tommy. - How're you doing, Henry?
你们好好的一起工作  好吗
You're gonna be working together, okay?
尽管帮他
Help him. Go ahead.
吉米  偷到什么好东西了吗
Jimmy, you got anything good?
警察曾经派出大军来捉吉米  他怎么做
And when the cops assigned a whole army to stop Jimmy, what did he do?
他把他们变成了同伙
He made them partners.
想抱怨也没人会听
I'd complain, but who'd listen?
- 一条帕尔玛尔  - 来
- One Pall Mall. - There you go.
- 你要什么  - 我要两条幸运红圈
- What do you need? - Two Luckies.
- 来  亨利  - 真多谢  要什么
- Here you go, Henry. - Thanks a lot... What do you need?
- 一条帕尔玛尔  - 一条帕尔玛尔  来
- One Pall Mall. - One Pall Mall, here you go.
- 你干什么  - 没有  没什么事
- What are you doing? - It's all right.
- 你有你妈的许可吗  - 你要几条烟呀
- You have permission from your mother? - How many cartons you need?
- 你从哪里弄来的香烟  - 把他弄走
- Where'd you get the cigarettes? - Get him out of here.
- 没关系的  - 有关系
- It's okay. - It's not okay.
- 你不明白  - 是你不明白  店关了
- You don't understand. - You don't understand. Store's closed.
- 亨利被捕了  - 在哪被捕
- Henry got pinched. - Where?
在工厂那里  他在卖烟
By the factory, selling cigarettes.
亨利·希尔  纽约州控诉亨利·希尔
Henry Hill. The People of the State of New York vs. Henry Hill.
案号704162
Docket number 704162.
是的  法官  我就是
Yes, sir. That's me.
走过来  站在那别动
Just stand there. Now stay there.
律师  继续吧
Counselor, proceed.
恭喜
Congratulations.
这是你的毕业礼物
Here's your graduation present.
- 为什么  我被捕了  - 每个人都会被捕  但你表现得很好
- What for? I got pinched. - Everyone does, but you did it right.
你什么也没说  他们也没得到线索
You told them nothing, and they got nothing.
- 我以为你会生气  - 我没生你的气  我为你骄傲
- I thought you'd be mad. - I'm not mad, I'm proud of you.
你初次被捕表现如男子汉  也学会了人生中最重要的两件事
You took your first pinch like a man and learned the two greatest things in life.
- 是什么  - 看着我
- What? - Look at me.
绝不背叛你的朋友
Never rat on your friends...
还有永不泄漏任何秘密
and always keep your mouth shut.
他来了
Here he is.
你有了第一次了
You broke your cherry.
恭喜你
Congratulations!
艾得伟机场  1963年
到我长大  每年从艾得伟机场
By the time I grew up, there was $30 billion a year in cargo...
进出的货值300亿
moving through Idlewild Airport...
你信不信  我们试图把它偷光
and believe me, we tried to steal every bit of it.
我们是在机场旁边混大的
See, you gotta understand, we grew up near the airport.
机场是属于保利的
It belonged to Paulie.
我们有亲戚朋友在各部门工作
We had friends and relatives who worked all over the place.
他们会告诉我们货物进出的消息
They would tip us off about what was coming in and moving out.
假如有航空公司或是卡车司机找我们麻烦
If any truckers or airlines gave us trouble...
保利和他的工会人员就以罢工吓他们  棒极了
Paulie had the union people scare them with a strike. It was beautiful.
这比彩票还赚  吉米就是管这档事的
It was a bigger moneymaker than numbers and Jimmy was in charge of it all.
我们一需要钱就抢机场
Whenever we needed money, we'd rob the airport.
比抢花旗银行还牛
To us, it was better than Citibank.
你有电话吗  快呀
You got a phone? Come on!
两个黑鬼偷了我的卡车  你相信这种事吗
Two niggers just stole my truck. Can you believe that shit?
吉米
There was Jimmy...
跟汤米还有我
and Tommy and me.
还有安东尼·史提保
And there was Anthony Stabile.
近来怎么样
How're you doing?
法兰克·卡本
Frankie Carbone.
还有毛黑的哥哥  肥佬安迪
And then there was Mo Black's brother, Fat Andy.
还有他的手下  意大利佬法兰基
And his guys, Frankie the Wop.
还有没鼻子佛莱迪
Freddy No Nose.
还有刽子手彼得  他是救世波尔的兄弟
And then there was Pete the Killer, who was Sally Balls'brother.
又有犀利眼尼基
Then you had Nickey Eyes...
还有米奇·法斯
and Mikey Franzese.
是呀  我想见他
That guy, I wanna see him.
还有由于什么话都说两遍而命名的二次奇米
Jimmy Two Times, who got that nickname because he said everything twice.
我要去拿报纸  拿报纸
I'm gonna go get the papers, get the papers.
这是什么  大衣  亨利  我要西装呀
What is this? Coats? Henry, I need suits, not coats.
西装呀  礼拜四会到
Suits are coming Thursday.
可是现在是夏天  你叫我怎么处理毛皮
But it's the middle of summer. What'll I do with fur coats?
你不要毛皮  那我把毛皮拿走
You don't want furs? I'll take them away.
不要拿走  我要用  我们把它们跟肉一起挂在冷冻库里
No, I want them. We'll hang them in the freezer with the meat. How's that?
要我们改变生活方式是不可能的
For us, to live any other way was nuts.
要我们跟那些老好人一样找份烂工作  钱又少
To us, those goody-good people who worked shitty jobs for bum paychecks...
每天挤地下铁上下班  帐单一大堆  不如死掉
and took the subway to work every day and worried about bills, were dead.
那些都是没勇气的弱者
They were suckers. They had no balls.
假如我们想要什么  我们就拿
If we wanted something, we just took it.
任何人敢抱怨两次以上  会被揍得不敢再抱怨第三次了
If anyone complained twice, they got hit so bad they never complained again.
一切都好像顺理成章  根本不用多伤脑筋
It was just all routine. You didn't even think about it.
520和469有什么关系
Frankie, what the fuck does 520 have to do with 469?
真不相信有这种人
I can't believe this guy.
520和469根本差太远了
520 ain't even close to 469. What's that got to do with anything?
简单得很  万事俱备
Piece of cake. It's all there.
不用担心警铃  我在想办法把钥匙弄到手
Don't worry about the alarms. I just gotta find a way to get the key.
- 不会有问题吧  - 我会把事弄妥的
- No problem, right? - I'll take care of it.
- 把你告诉我的事告诉他  - 好得难以置信
- Tell him what you were telling me. - Too good to be true.
法国航空公司有大生意了  有一袋袋的钱要托运
Big score coming from Air France. Bags of money coming in.
美国的观光客和军人  他们把美金换成法郎
Tourists and American servicemen change their money...
美金又被运回来
into French money and send it back here.
- 冷静一点  - 太美了
- Calm down. - It's beautiful.
完全无法追踪
It's totally untraceable. Okay?
唯一的问题就是怎么拿到钥匙  但我已经想到办法了
The only problem is getting a key, but I've got a plan.
- 我和法国佬和这个国民  - 这笨蛋很容易操纵的
- Me and Frenchy and this citizen. - Yeah, he's a piece of work.
假如我估计正确  那里有50万现金
If I'm right, there could be $500,000 coming in, all cash.
他说最好在周末下手  也许礼拜六晚上
The best time is probably over a weekend. So maybe Saturday night.
礼拜一是犹太教假日
There's a Jewish holiday on Monday.
要到礼拜二才会被发现  太美了
They won't find out until Tuesday. Beautiful.
警卫怎么办
What about the security?
警卫吗
Security?
这位就是  笑死了  我就是午夜到早上八点的班
You're looking at it. It's a joke. I'm the midnight-to-eight man.
我就是总司令
I'm the commandant.
他就像来招领失物一样就行了
He just comes in like he's picking up lost baggage.
- 太美了  - 不会出任何问题的
- It's beautiful. - It won't be a problem at all.
- 好  - 就这么办
- Good. - We're on.
最可笑的是在席考克斯抢银行那一次
What's really funny is that fucking bank job in Secaucus.
我正躺在草里
I'm in the middle of the weeds, lying down.
警察走过来问我  你在干什么
He says, "What are you doing?"
我说  我在休息呀
I said, "I'm resting."
这不是公园或海滩  我说  我在休息
"Here? This ain't no beach or park." I said, "I'm resting."
他们把我捉进去问东问西
He pulls me in, starts asking questions. You know, this and that.
你要告诉我们些什么呢  我说  一如往常  零
"What are you going to tell us?" I said, "My usual. Nothing."
为什么要告诉你  干  他说  今天你非说不可
"Why tell you?" The fuck. He says, "No, you'll tell me something today."
我说  那好  你去操你妈吧
I said, "Okay, go fuck your mother."
你看报纸了没有  安东尼  我的头肿得这么大
You saw the paper, Anthony. My head was out like this.
当我醒过来
Now I'm coming around, and who do I see in front of me?
这死家伙又站在我面前  你现在还有什么话说
This prick again. He says, "What do you want to tell me now?"
你在这儿干嘛  我不是叫你去操你妈吗
I said, "What are you doing here? I told you to go fuck your mother."
我以为他会拉在裤子里
I thought he was gonna shit.
我又被揍了一顿  那时候我真希望我是个大个子
The fuckers. I wish I was big just once.
真好玩  真滑稽
Funny. You're really funny.
你是什么意思
What do you mean, I'm funny?
就是好玩  我是说你的故事很搞笑
It's funny, you know. It's a good story.
你很幽默
You're a funny guy.
你说我讲话的样子吗
You mean the way I talk? What?
只是  你很有趣
It's just, you know. You're just funny.
你讲事情经过的样子  很有趣
You know, the way you tell the story and everything.
滑稽  好玩  有什么好玩
Funny how? What's funny about it?
- 汤米  你误会了  - 安东尼
- Tommy, you got it all wrong. - Anthony.
他又不是小孩子  让他自己解释  到底怎么有趣法
He's a big boy. He knows what he said. What did you say?
只是  你就是很有趣嘛
Just, you know. You're funny.
让我把事情弄清楚
Let me understand this.
也许我有点醉了
Maybe I'm a little fucked up.
但我是怎么个有趣法  像小丑一样吗
But, I'm funny, how? Funny like a clown? I amuse you?
我是来逗你开心的吗
I make you laugh? I'm here to fucking amuse you?
我到底是哪里滑稽
What do you mean, funny? How am I funny?
你也知道嘛  就是你讲故事的方式
You know, how you tell a story.
不  我不懂  是你说的
No, I don't know. You said it. How do I know? You said I'm funny.
我到底是哪里滑稽
How the fuck am I funny? What the fuck is so funny about me?
我哪里有趣  告诉我呀
Tell me what's funny.
你有完没完呀  汤米
Get the fuck out of here, Tommy.
他妈的  他差点被我唬住了
Motherfucker! I almost had him!
你这个讲话结巴的死家伙  你
You stuttering prick, you!
法兰基  他有没有发抖
Frankie, was he shaking?
我真担心你  亨利  你经不起拷问
I wonder about you sometimes, Henry. You may fold under questioning.
耶稣基督啊
Jesus Christ.
你在搞什么呀  我还以为我被捕了
What the fuck is it with you? I thought I was getting pinched already.
他靠着我脖子  好像秃鹰一样  你要什么
He's hanging on my fucking neck like a vulture. What do you want?
伙计他说不敢把帐单拿过来给你
This guy didn't want to come and give you the check.
你能不能结一下帐
Could you take care of this?
没问题  叫他记在我帐上
No problem. Tell him to put it on my tab. Of course.
我就是想跟你商量一下
That's what I want to talk to you about.
你的帐不只这些  你还欠我七千
It ain't just this one. It's seven big ones you owe me.
已经到七千块了  不是小数目  我也不想失礼
$7,000, that ain't peanuts. I don't mean to be out of order...
你不想失礼
Don't mean to be out of order?
好在你不想失礼
It's good you don't mean to be out of order.
在我朋友面前说我赖帐
Embarrassing me in front of my friends, like I'm a deadbeat.
你知道吗  桑尼  你真他妈的够贱的
You know, Sonny, you're a fucking mutt.
我们在你这里消费了多少
You know the money we spend in this fucking...
- 别这样嘛  - 什么别这样
- Don't be like that. - What do you mean?
世界上真有这种人  你觉得这个有趣吗
Do you believe this prick? You think this is funny?
你他妈的看什么  你这个白痴
What the fuck are you looking at? You fucking moron!
你不愿意拿帐单给我是不是
You don't want to bring the check?
真有这种人
Do you believe this prick?
你也应该对他们狠一点
You're supposed to be doing this stuff, too.
你真有意思
You're a funny guy.
- 这次你完了  亨利  - 不要这样  坐下
- That's it, Henry. - No, go back.
你想笑吗  这混蛋上礼拜还叫我给他儿子洗礼呢
You want to laugh? This prick last week asked me to christen his kid.
我就算他七千块吧
I charged him $7,000.
你真笑死我了
You really are a funny guy.
我很担心  我听到些奇奇怪怪的事
I'm worried. I'm hearing all kinds of fucking bad things.
汤米对待我的方式就好像我是什么怪物  同性恋似的
He's treating me like I'm a fucking fag.
我没办法逃避他
I got to go on the lam in order to get away from this guy.
他这样是不对的  我没地方好去
This ain't right. I can't go here, I can't go there.
不是只有你  我跟兄弟们说了很多次了  他们不听
You think you're the only one? I talk to them, they don't listen.
假如你跟他说  他会听的
If you tell him, he'll stop. I'll wind up being declared an MIA.
否则我会被发现死在后车厢或草丛里
They'll find me in the back of a car somewhere in the weeds.
没人比你更清楚汤米
You've known this Tommy all your life. Who knows better?
这家伙是终极罪犯
This cocksucker's an arch criminal.
我每天出门的时候都担心会遭暗算
When I leave my house, before I get to the car I look over both shoulders.
我没法活下去了
This is no way to live. I'm no fence jumper.
我跟了你一辈子  你说我该怎么办
I'm around you all my life, tell me what I gotta do.
- 我必须怎么做  就怎么做  - 我能做什么呢
- Whatever I got to do, I'm gonna do. - What could I do?
如果我能帮上忙  我一定会做的
If there was something I could do, I would. I would like to help you out.
桑尼  告诉他我们谈的事
Sonny, tell him what we talked about.
- 你觉得妥当吗  - 说吧
- You think it's all right? - Yeah.
我希望你成为我店里的股东之一  那就好了
Maybe you could come in with me, take a piece of this joint. It'd be good.
你在说什么  你是说餐厅
What are you talking about? You mean the restaurant?
那是个高级地方
It's a classy place. Look at the layout.
你去过很多次了
You've been in there a million times. You know how it looks.
如果汤米接去做  简直像给猪戴丝帽一样
Tommy taking over this joint is like putting a silk hat on a pig.
我不是看不起他  事实是如此
I don't mean no disrespect, but that's the way it is.
我还能说什么  我是在求你
I know you're his friend. I'm begging you. What can I say?
我能做什么
What am I gonna do? What do you want from me?
我对餐厅一窍不通
I don't know anything about the restaurant business. Nothing.
我只会点菜而已
All I know is to sit down and order a meal, not how to make a restaurant.
不是要你去管理  你只是多一个地方走动而已
Not for you. It's just a place to hang.
那里的厨师很棒  表演也很好  漂亮小妞也多
The chef is great. The shows are good. There's a lot of whores coming in.
我真的很愿意帮你  你要我怎么做
I'd love to help you, but what do you want from me? What'll I do?
汤米是够坏的  难道要我枪毙他
Tommy's a bad kid, a bad seed. What am I supposed to do? Shoot him?
这倒不是个坏主意
That wouldn't be a bad idea.
对不起  我不是真心的  只是他令我害怕
I'm sorry I said that. I didn't mean it. I just mean that he's scaring me.
我需要你的帮忙  求求你
I just need help. Help me, please.
餐厅生意你懂吗
You know anything about this restaurant business?
他什么都懂  他从早到晚都在那里
He knows everything. He's there 24 hours a day.
他就像那里的椅子一样
Another fucking few minutes, he could be a stool.
永远都在里面
That's how often he's in there.
你要我做你的股东  搞了半天就是要我做你的股东是吗
You want me to be your partner? Is that what you're telling me?
你以为我在说什么  好不好  保利
What the fuck you think I'm talking about? Paulie, please. Come on.
那太不公平了
It's not even fair.
别这么说
You don't understand.
好吧  你管理  我来从旁协助
You run the joint. Maybe I'll try to help you, all right.
上帝保佑你  保利  我真的很感激你  你对我真好
God bless you, Paulie. I appreciate it. You've always been fair with me.
现在桑尼有保利撑腰了  发生任何问题他都找保利
Now the guy's got Paulie as a partner. Any problems, he goes to Paulie.
有人不付钱  他就找保利
Trouble with a bill, he can go to Paulie.
警察  送货的  甚至汤米给他找麻烦
Trouble with the cops, deliveries, Tommy...
他都能去找保利
he can call Paulie.
可是现在他每星期得付保利保护费
Now the guy's gotta come up with Paulie's money every week...
无论状况如何
no matter what.
生意不好吗  去你的  付钱  店失火啦  去你的  付钱
"Business is bad? Fuck you, pay me. Had a fire? Fuck you, pay me.
店被雷击中啦  去你的  付钱
"The place got hit by lightning? Fuck you, pay me."
电视机给我一台好不好
Can I get one of those TVs?
保利可以为所欲为
Also, Paulie could do anything.
特别是拿餐厅的信贷到处消费
Especially run up bills on the joint's credit. And why not?
反正不准备付钱的
Nobody's gonna pay for it anyway.
货一旦从前门进
When deliveries are made at the front door...
就送出后门廉价拍卖
you move the stuff out the back and sell it at a discount.
二百块的一箱酒一百块卖出去
You take a $200 case of booze and sell it for $100.
也不要紧  反正都是净赚
It doesn't matter. It's all profit.
到最后
Then finally, when there's nothing left...
真他妈够可惜了
Fucking shame.
别人不再借钱给你  厂商也不再送货了
...when you can't borrow another buck or buy another case of booze...
你只好点根火柴把店烧了  领保险金
you bust the joint out. You light a match.
有什么够不到的  需要我帮你吗
Do you need help reaching anything?
你像在装饰一颗圣诞树一样
You look like you're decorating a Christmas tree.
你根本什么都不会
You don't know what you're doing.
她是从富人区来的
She's from the Five Towns.
谁呀
Who?
那个犹太马子  戴安  我想跟她上床
The Jew broad, Diane, I was telling you I'm going to shag.
我已经试了一个月了
I've been trying to bang her for a fucking month now.
问题就是她从不肯跟我单独约会
She won't go out with me alone.
- 不  - 什么不
- No. - No, what?
不什么  我又没请你
No, what? Who the fuck asked you anything?
我又没问你  至少听我说完好不好
I didn't ask you. Hear what I'm going to say.
好啦  什么啦
All right, what?
好啦  是这样
Okay, what.
她不肯跟意大利人出去
She don't want to go out with Italians alone.
她对意大利人有偏见
She's prejudiced against Italians.
什么时候了  还有这种事
You fucking believe that? In this day and age?
这是什么世界啊
What the fuck is this world coming to?
难以相信  一个犹太马子对意大利人有偏见
I can't believe this. A Jew broad, prejudiced against Italians.
除非和她的女朋友一起  她绝不单独跟我约会
She won't go out with me alone unless her girlfriend comes with us.
所以我想你可以当她女朋友的伴
So you come along, go out with her girlfriend.
看吧  我就知道
See? I knew it.
你知道什么  有什么不好
You knew what? What the fuck is wrong with that?
- 什么时候  - 明天晚上
- When is this? - Tomorrow night.
明晚不行  我要见杜迪
I can't, I gotta meet Tuddy.
你可以早点出来  事后再去见杜迪
You could meet Tuddy. You can come early and then still go.
- 你怎么老是这样  - 别找理由了
- Why do you always do this? - Don't give me that shit.
我是找你帮忙
What did I ask you for? I'm asking you for a favor.
我帮过你不少忙的
I do a lot of fucking favors for you.
我想搞那娘们  你懂不懂
I'm trying to bang this fucking broad. Help me out.
她真的很漂亮
I don't understand you. She's beautiful!
住在高级区  这些犹太女孩很有钱
Her fucking family lives in the Five Towns. These Jews got money.
说不定整条街都是她家的  你也许会中头奖也不一定
Maybe the family owns the whole block. You may wind up with a big score.
光听你讲犹太女朋友好了
You with your fucking mouth.
我约了杜迪十一点见  现在我正在给汤米做搭档
I had a meeting with Tuddy at 11:00, and here I am, a backup guy for Tommy.
你吃饱了吗
How about it? Did you have enough to eat?
很好吃  我正在节食
It was delicious. I'm just watching my diet.
让我替你注意身材就好了
Let me watch your figure.
我等不及离开
I couldn't wait to get away.
他们还在吃主菜  我就已经叫点心了
I was ordering the dessert when they were eating dinner.
他们还在喝咖啡  我就先结帐了
When they were having coffee, I was asking for a check.
我有事情
I had business.
喝点咖啡吧  会清醒一点
Have some coffee. It'll wake you up.
- 帐单给我  - 你急什么呀
- Can we have the check? - What are you doing?
- 我得走了  - 我们才刚到
- I got to go. - We just got here.
我还有事  我要走了
I got that thing. I gotta go.
再等几分钟  我们一起离开好吗
Wait a couple of minutes. We'll leave together.
这样才不会像一群流浪汉  一个一个走
This way we don't go out like a bunch of hobos, one at a time.
我受不了他
I couldn't stand him.
我觉得他真的很倒胃口
I thought he was really obnoxious.
四肢一直摆弄着
He kept fidgeting around.
可不可以不要玩打火机  很烦
You don't mind, do you? That's very annoying.
也许甜酒比较适合你  但我喝就不像样了
Good? You might prefer Manischewitz, but it'd look funny on my table.
- 可以走了吧  - 亨利  放松一点嘛
- Ready? - Henry, lighten up.
我们才刚到  别紧张  好不好
We just got here. What are you doing?
回家的时候还没到  他就把我推进车门
Before it was time to go home, he was pushing me into the car...
又拉了出来  太荒唐了
then pulling me out. It was ridiculous.
戴安和汤米
Diane and Tommy made us promise...
又约我们星期五见
to meet them again on Friday night.
我们答应了
We agreed.
果不其然  星期五晚上亨利没来
Of course, when Friday night came around, Henry stood me up.
真抱歉  我不知道他在哪
I feel terrible. I don't know where he is.
可是他真的很喜欢你  他一直不停地谈她
He really liked you, too. All he did was talk about her.
那天约会之夜只有我们三个人
We were a trio instead of a double date that night.
他该来通电话  我真担心  希望不是太严重
He would have called. I hope it's nothing serious.
我逼汤米带我去找他
But I made Tommy take me looking for him.
汤米  你搞什么
Tommy, what the fuck?
你真有种呀  跟我爽约
You got some nerve standing me up.
从来没有人敢这样对我
Nobody does that to me.
你以为你是谁  像法兰奇·瓦利那样的大歌星吗
Who do you think you are, Frankie Valli or some kind of big shot?
慢着好不好  我忘了  我以为是下星期
Slow down, I forgot. I thought it was next week.
是这个星期五  你答应的  你这个骗子
It was this Friday and you agreed, so you're a liar!
别这样  别这样  我们好好谈一下
We can talk about this. Take it easy.
有什么好谈的
Talk about it?
去你的吧  我们没什么好谈的
Talk to you after what you just did to me? Forget it.
我以为你不会来的  你那天什么也不说  一副无聊的样子
I thought you would stand me up. You looked bored. You didn't say anything.
再给我一次补偿的机会吧
Let me make it up to you.
让我考虑一下
I'll think about it.
我记得她在街上大喊大叫
I remember, she was screaming on the street, and I mean loud.
可是看起来真动人
But she looked good.
我会考虑考虑  不过有代价的  希尔
I'll think about it. But it'll cost you, Hill. A lot.
她的眼睛真美  就像伊莉莎白·泰勒（好莱坞女星）一样
She had these great eyes just like Liz Taylor's.
至少我这么觉得
At least that's what I thought.
哈罗  亨利
Hello, Henry.
- 你准备好了吗  - 好了
- You're ready? - Yeah.
那走吧
Come on.
- 不  等一下  - 什么
- No, wait a minute. - What?
快  把十字架盖起来  我妈看到她会认为你是基督徒（犹太人不信基督教）
Quick, you have to cover that cross. My mother sees that...
凯伦
Karen.
妈
Mom.
- 这是我朋友亨利·希尔  - 你好吗
- I'd like you to meet my friend, Henry Hill. - How do you do?
我女儿说你是半个犹太人
My daughter says that you're half Jewish.
好的一半是
It's just the good half.
- 谢谢  先生  - 谢谢
- Thank you, sir. - Bye, see you later, thanks.
你干嘛把车停在这里
What're you doing? You're leaving your car?
他会替我看着
He watches the car for me.
比停在停车场快多了
It's easier than leaving it at a garage and waiting.
这样快多了  懂我意思吗
It's a lot quicker that way, you know what I mean?
我喜欢从这里走  比排队好
I like going in this way. It's better than waiting in line.
你好  一切都好吧  这给你
How are you doing? What's up? Here you go.
- 你好吗  - 你好
- How are you doing? - I'm doing all right.
我每次来  你们两个都在这里  不用工作吗
Every time I come here, every time, you two. Don't you work?
你好吗  嗨  你好吗
Henry, nice to see you. Hi, how are you?
安东尼  摆在最前面
Anthony, right in the front.
如果需要什么  告诉我就好了
Anything you need, just let me know.
东尼  真是谢了  我很感激
Tony, thanks a lot. I appreciate it.
- 你给他们每人二十块钱  - 没关系的
- You gave them $20 each. - It's all right.
亨利  这是东尼先生送的
Henry, this is with Mr. Tony, over there.
- 在哪里  - 就在这边
- Where? - Over there.
谢了  东尼
Thanks a lot, Tony.
- 你靠什么生活  - 什么
- What do you do? - What?
- 你靠什么生活  - 我在建筑界
- What do you do? - I'm in construction.
这双手不像做建筑的
They don't feel like you're in construction.
我是工会代表
I'm a union delegate.
各位女士  先生
Now, ladies and gentlemen...
很荣幸为各位介绍单句笑话之王
the Copacabana is proud to present the king of one-liners...
亨利·洋曼
Henny Youngman.
各位好  我能在这里表演感到骄傲  请把我太太带走
How are you all? I'm glad to be here. Take my wife, please.
不论我把我太太丢在什么地方  她总会回家
I take my wife everywhere but she finds her way home.
我问她要去哪里庆祝结婚纪念
I said, "Where do you wanna go for our anniversary?"
她说要到一个她从来没去过的地方
She said, "Somewhere I've never been before."
我说  那就去厨房好了
I said, "Try the kitchen."
韦士勒医生在场
Dr. Wellsler is here.
给病人估计还能活六个月  时候到了却缴不出来医药费
Gave a guy six months to live. Couldn't pay his bill.
他又告诉病人还能再活六个月
Gave him another six months.
我真喜欢你们
I love this crowd.
非工作人员止步
是法国航空让我成功的
Air France made me.
连枪都没有用就抢走了42万
We walked out with $420,000 without using a gun.
当然也给了保利他应得的保护费
And we did the right thing. We gave Paulie his tribute.
6万元
$60,000.
我们会过一个好夏天
It's going to be a good summer.
我为你骄傲  对你这个年纪  那是笔大数目
I'm proud of you. That is a lot of money for a kid like you.
任何人问起来  就说是在赌城赢的
Anybody asks you where you got it, you got it in Vegas playing craps, all right?
好的
All right.
先生  帐单
Check, sir.
别拿大票子  在这里是用签名的
No. You have to sign for it here.
要不要给他小费
Should I tip him?
- 你好吗  - 很好  你呢
- How are you doing? - Okay. How are you?
亨利  这是布鲁斯  布鲁斯  这是亨利
Henry, this is Bruce. Bruce, this is Henry.
你好吗
Good to meet you.
有机会再聚
I'll see you around later.
- 你认识他吗  - 是呀
- Do you know him? - Yeah.
住我家对面
He lives across the street.
有一天晚上  巴比·云顿送我们无比可口的香槟酒
One night, Bobby Vinton sent us champagne. There was nothing like it.
一个21岁的年轻人有这样的关系
I didn't think there was anything strange in any of this.
我并不感到奇怪
A 21-year-old kid with such connections.
跟他在一起很刺激
He was an exciting guy.
他对我很好  把我介绍给他所有的朋友
He was really nice. He introduced me to everybody.
每个人都对他很好
Everybody wanted to be nice to him.
他也应对得很得体
He knew how to handle it.
不要买会掉下来的假发
Don't buy wigs that come off at the wrong time.
摩里的假发不会掉下来
Morrie's wigs don't come off!
在水中也没事
Even underwater.
在狂风中也安然无恙
And remember, Morrie's wigs are tested against hurricane winds.
别担心价钱  价钱不是问题
Forget about money. You can afford a Morrie wig. Priced to fit every budget.
来电话
Call me now!
约时间试试看吧
Come in for a personalized fitting.
走呀  摩里  吉米在等着  你欠的钱已经过期了
Come on, Morrie. Jimmy's waiting. You're past due.
你这个人不错  我对你不错  你对我也不错
You're a good kid. We've been good to each other.
但有些事不合理
But there's something unreasonable going on here.
吉米太狠了
Jimmy's being a ball-breaker.
我赌克里夫兰队  下注8:5
Give him 8-to-5 on Cleveland.
我没法付那么高的利息
I never had to pay the vigorish he demands. Am I something special?
你以为我是什么  白痴呀
What am I, a schmuck on wheels?
你向吉米借了钱  你就该还给他
You know Jimmy. You borrowed his money. Pay him.
我没同意高利之外又加三分
I didn't agree to three points above the vig.
你要怎么样嘛  你要对付吉米吗
What are you going to do? Fight with Jimmy Conway?
他要他的钱  你付了钱  我好走路呀
He wants his money. Give him his money and we'll go.
去他的吧
Fuck him!
操他耳朵啦  操他另外一只耳朵
Fuck him in the ear! Fuck him in the other ear!
我有没有给他出过漏子
Did I ever bust his balls? Did I?
我只要一通电话给条子  我就什么钱也不用付了
I could've dropped a dime a million times.
别发疯了  好不好
You're talking crazy. Stop it now, will you?
你有钱去做电视广告
You got money for that fucking commercial.
没钱还给我是吧
You don't got my money?
吉米  他会还给你的
Jimmy, he's gonna pay you.
我要宰了你  你这个奴才  钱拿给我
I'll fucking kill you. Give me the money, cocksucker.
把钱还我
Pay me my money.
他会付
He'll pay.
摩里假发  是谁  他在这儿
Morrie's. Who's this? He's here.
- 对不起  吉米  - 你应该对不起
- Jimmy, I'm sorry. - You should be sorry.
把钱还我  再有一次你就完了
Don't do it again. Give me the fucking money!
你听着  把钱还给我
You hear me? Give me the fucking money.
我会给  我会给
I'll give you. You've got it, kid. You've got it, believe me.
凯伦  慢慢讲嘛
Karen, slow down.
哪里  就在那里  不要走开
Where? Stay there. Don't move.
- 发生了什么事  - 是凯伦  吉米
- What happened? - It's Karen, Jimmy.
- 今天就付  - 我会付
- Money today. - I'll pay.
发生了什么事
What happened?
- 你还好吗  - 我没事
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
是谁干的
Who did it?
住在我家对面  我从小就认识的一个家伙
This guy who lives across the street from me that I've known all my life.
他开始摸我  抓我
He started to touch me. He stared to grab me.
我叫他住手  他不听
I told him to stop. He didn't stop.
我就打他  结果他发火了
I hit him back. And then he got really angry.
把我推出车外
He pushed me out of the car.
你确定你没事吗
You sure you're all right?
你进去吧  整理一下  梳洗干净
Why don't you go inside and get yourself together. Clean up.
你想干什么  败类  你想要什么吗
What do you want, fucko? You want something?
以我母亲的名义发誓  你再碰凯伦一下  你就死定了
I swear on my fucking mother, if you touch her again, you're dead.
不要开枪
Don't shoot.
- 把枪藏起来  你没事吧  - 没事
- Hide this. Are you all right? - Yeah.
我知道  一般女孩一定会和男朋友分手
I know there are women, like my best friends...
如果她男朋友拿一支枪
who would have gotten out the minute their boyfriend...
叫她拿去藏起来  但我没有
gave them a gun to hide. But I didn't.
老实说  我觉得这很刺激
I've got to admit the truth. It turned me on.
恭喜
Mazel tov!
你为什么不学亨利  他就有个好姑娘在身边
Why don't you be like your friend Henry? He's got a nice girl.
他要安定了  妻子都娶了
He's settling down now. He's married.
不久就有个小家庭了
Pretty soon he'll have a nice family.
你老是一个接一个的换
And you're still bouncing around from girl to girl.
亨利好像有两个家庭
It was like he had two families.
他把他们介绍给我时真是多到疯掉
The first time I was introduced to all of them at once, it was crazy.
保利和他的兄弟们都有一大堆孩子
Paulie and his brothers had lots of sons and nephews.
几乎都叫彼德或保罗
Almost all of them were named Peter or Paul.
简直不敢相信
It was unbelievable.
这位是我侄儿小保利  然后这是彼迪
Meet Paulie Jr., my nephew. And this is Petey.
婚礼中起码有两打以上的彼德和保罗
There must have been two dozen Peters and Pauls at the wedding.
这是玛莉
This is Marie.
他们的妻子也都叫玛莉
Plus, they were all married to girls named Marie.
- 看起来像意大利人  - 没错  她就是意大利人
- She looks Italian. - She is Italian, you're right.
他们的女儿也都叫玛莉
And they named all their daughters Marie.
这是彼德  不  是保利  我有时也会弄错
And this is Pete. No, I mean Paulie. I get confused myself.
当我和每个人打过招呼后  我以为我醉了
By the time I finished meeting everybody, I thought I was drunk.
保利  你太客气了
Paulie, you shouldn't have.
欢迎你成为家庭中的一份子
Welcome to the family.
星期日来我家晚餐
Sunday dinner?
真漂亮  我真想哭
So beautiful. I want to cry.
小小意思  可以帮你们建立一个家庭
Here's something to help you get started.
- 那个袋子  那个袋子呢  - 什么袋子
- The bag. The bag. - What? What bag?
那个装满了信封和钱的袋子呀
The bag with the envelopes in it, all the money.
别担心  没人会偷的
Don't worry about that. Nobody's going to steal that here.
他连电话都没打
He didn't call?
- 他和朋友在一起  - 他是什么人  连电话都不打
- He's with his friends. - What kind of person doesn't call?
妈  他是成人  不需要每五分钟来一个电话
He's a grown-up. He doesn't have to call every five minutes.
如果是成人  为什么不搬出去住
If he was such a grown-up why doesn't he get you two an apartment?
妈  是你要我们住在这里的
Don't start. Mom, you're the one who wanted us here.
听着  你在这里一个月了  我知道他经常不回家
You're here a month and sometimes I know he doesn't come home at all.
他们到底是什么样的人
What kind of people are these?
- 妈  你要我怎么样  - 你能怎么样
- What do you want me to do? - Do? What can you do?
他又不是犹太人  你了解他们吗
He's not Jewish. Did you know how these people live?
你爸爸可不是整夜不归  电话也不打
Your father never stayed out all night without calling.
整夜不归  爸爸连门都不出  妈  你少管我们
Stay out? Daddy never went out at all, Ma! Keep out of it.
你不明白我的感觉
You don't know how I feel!
你有什么感觉
How do you feel now?
既不知道他在哪里  也不知道他和什么人在一起
You don't know where he is or who he's with.
他和朋友在一起  爸爸
He's with his friends! Dad!
不要把你爸爸扯进来
Leave him out of this. He's suffered enough.
他已经有六星期消化不良了
He hasn't digested a decent meal in six weeks.
你去了些什么地方  为什么不打电话
Where were you? Why didn't you call?
我们担心死了  已婚男人不该整夜不归
We were worried to death. A married man does not stay out like this.
正常人没有这种行为的
Normal people don't act like this!
你哪里不对劲
What's wrong with you?
她没说错  你是不正常  你哪里不对劲
You're not normal. She's right. What's wrong with you?
你有什么毛病  你是什么样的人
What kind of person are you? What is the matter with you?
他们那些家伙是哪种人
What kind of people are they?
我们嫁的不是上班族
We weren't married to nine-to-five guys.
让我感到有多不同
But the first time I realized how different...
是在美琪的家庭聚会时
was when Mickey had a hostess party.
- 凯伦  你是哪里人  - 劳伦斯
- Karen, where you from? - Lawrence.
在长岛  不错呀  我生在迈阿密  你去过吗
On the Island. It's nice. I'm from Miami. You ever been there?
那里还不错  像个犹太天堂
It's okay, but it's like you died and woke up in Jew heaven.
不要老挤痘子嘛
Angie, stop picking at that thing.
我真想揍他的脸
I'd like to smack his face.
那个红发男人
The red-haired guy, looks like a farmer?
他都要动手动脚的
The guy's hands are all over me.
我说  不要对我动手  否则我把它切下来
So I told him, "Keep your fucking hands off me, or I'll cut them off."
她是认真的
She means it.
他不知道多走运  如果我告诉韦力
You don't know how lucky he is. I just mention this to Vinnie...
你怎么能告诉韦力  他非杀了他不可
How can you mention it? Vinnie would kill him.
说出来  韦力杀了他  又得去坐一辈子牢
If I don't, he'll kill the miserable bastard, then Vinnie will be there for life.
你以为只有你有麻烦呀  珍妮的儿子更糟
You think you got problems. What about Jeannie's kid?
在一场只有10元输赢的扑克中和人争执起来  他拿出枪
He was in an argument. A $10 card game. He pulls out a gun.
枪走火  打死一个男孩  当他祖母听到他在牢里
The gun goes off. Some kid gets killed. When the grandmother hears it...
心脏病发作  当场就死了
and finds out he's jailed, she has a heart attack and drops dead right on the spot.
现在珍妮的老公和孩子在牢里  妈妈在殡仪馆
Now Jeannie has a husband and son in jail and a mother in the funeral parlor.
- 珍妮酗酒  - 也许她是心情不好
- Jeannie drinks. - Maybe she's depressed.
饶了我吧  她根本就是酗酒
Give me a break. She's drunk.
只要有点事发生  他们都成圣人了
As soon as something happens, you make them out to be saints.
她们皮肤粗糙  化妆太浓  气色不好
They had bad skin and wore too much makeup. They didn't look very good.
她们看起来很憔悴  穿的衣服
They looked beat-up. And the stuff they wore...
也是不成套的廉价品
was thrown together and cheap.
都是些裤装  针织品
A lot of pantsuits and double-knits.
她昼夜穿睡袍
She spends her life in a nightgown.
相信我  她不是什么好东西
The woman is no angel, believe me.
她们谈论着她们的孩子多坏
They talked about their rotten kids...
她们用扫把揍孩子  她们用皮鞭揍孩子
and about beating them with broom handles and belts.
但孩子们一点也不理会
And that the kids still didn't pay any attention.
当亨利来接我的时候  我整个头都晕了
When Henry picked me up, I was dizzy.
我不知道我能不能适应这种生活
I don't know if I could live like that.
你要是进了监牢  我怎么办
God forbid, what would happen if you had to go to prison?
凯伦
Karen.
美琪谈到了珍妮的丈夫
Mickey said that Jeannie's husband...
你知道怎么回事吗
Do you know why Jeannie's husband went to the can?
珍妮的丈夫是为了逃避珍妮才去坐牢的
Because of Jeannie. He wanted to get away from her.
你听我说  坐牢的都是想坐牢的
Let me tell you something. Nobody goes to jail unless they want to.
都是甘愿被捕的
Unless they make themselves get caught.
他们没把事情安排好
They don't have things organized.
我都把事弄妥了
I know what I'm doing. I've got things organized with these guys.
你知道哪些人坐牢吗
You know who goes to jail?
黑人抢劫犯  你知道他们为什么会被捕吗
Nigger stickup men. You know why they get caught?
因为他们在逃走用的车上睡着了
Because they fall asleep in the getaway car, Karen.
凯伦  不要瞎担心了  甜心  过来吧
Come on, don't worry so much, sweetie. Come here.
渐渐地  一切都好像很正常了
After a while, it got to be all normal.
没有一样像犯罪
None of it seemed like crime.
亨利就像在经营企业
It was more like Henry was enterprising...
他和伙伴以诈骗为生而已
and that he and the guys made bucks hustling while other guys...
至少他们不坐着等别人来救济
were sitting on their asses waiting for handouts.
我们的丈夫不是脑外科医生  他们是靠努力赚钱的
Our husbands weren't brain surgeons, they were blue-collar guys.
他们只有多偷  多抢  才能多赚点钱
The only way they could make real extra money was to go out and cut corners.
钱箱在那里  讨人厌的东西
Where's the strong box, you varmint?
你他妈的别动
Don't fucking move! Don't move.
- 餐厅见了  - 我坐副驾驶座
- See you at the diner. - I'm riding shotgun.
你看他刚才立刻就服软了
Did you see him give it right over?
走吧  回老巢去分钱吧
Back to the hideout to split up the loot.
我们非常亲近
We were all so very close.
从来不跟外人来往  绝不
There were never any outsiders around. Absolutely never.
就因为这样  一切好像更正常了
Being together all the time made everything seem all the more normal.
哈罗  希尔太太  警察
Hello, Mrs. Hill. Police.
我是迪西警探  他是席维思警探  我们有搜查令
I'm Detective Deacy. This is Detective Silvestri. We have a search warrant.
请看一下  然后签名
Would you read and sign it?
- 哪里都行吗  - 是的
- Anywhere? - Yeah, anywhere.
要耽误一点时间  我们每样都要仔细查
This'll take a while, we have to go through everything.
- 你们要咖啡吗  - 不用了  谢谢你
- You boys want some coffee? - No coffee now, thanks.
- 请当心点  - 我们只是照常执行任务
- Be careful. - We'll just go about our business.
警察经常会找些小麻烦
There was always a little harassment.
他们要跟亨利谈东谈西
They wanted to talk to Henry about this or that.
他们带着传票和搜查令来叫我签名
They'd make me sign their subpoenas or warrants.
不论他们搜到什么
But mostly they just wanted a handout.
几块钱也就把他们打发了
A few bucks to keep things quiet no matter what they found.
我每次都问他们  要不要咖啡  有的太太  像美琪
I always asked if they wanted coffee. Some wives, like Mickey Conway...
她总是诅咒他们  还吐口水在地板上
used to curse at them and spit on the floor.
我永远也不了解为什么要吐在自己的地板上
She used to spit on her own floor. That never made any sense to me.
还是礼貌一点  然后打电话给律师比较好
It was better to be polite and call the lawyer.
我们总是在一起  总是同样一群人
We always did everything together, and we always were in the same crowd.
纪念日  受洗等等  我们只到彼此的家去
Anniversaries, christenings. We only went to each other's houses.
女士们一起玩牌
The women played cards.
凡有婴儿诞生  美琪和吉米总是最先到医院的
When kids were born, Mickey and Jimmy were the first at the hospital.
当我们去南海或赌城度假
When we went to the Islands or Vegas for vacation...
也都是一起的
we went together.
从来没有外人  好像那才是正常的
No outsiders ever. It got to be normal.
我甚至对我丈夫的所作所为
It got to where I was proud that I had the kind of husband...
感到骄傲
who was willing to risk his neck just to get us the little extras.
我已经跟妈讲好了  明晚来替我们看孩子
But I got Mom to watch the babies tomorrow night.
- 我没办法  凯伦  - 为什么
- Can't do it, Karen. - Why not?
就是不行嘛  我已安排好别的事了
I just can't. I got something lined up.
但妈妈只有明晚可以替我们看孩子
But tomorrow's the only night she can do it.
- 拜托嘛  好不好  - 我真的不行  你要我怎么办
- Pretty please? - I can't. What do you want me to do?
- 我得走了  - 等一下
- I got to go. - Wait a minute.
我要去逛街  给我点钱好吗
I wanted to go shopping. Can I get some money?
你需要多少
How much do you need?
- 多少  - 这么多
- How much? - That much.
这么多  亲我一下
This much. Give me a kiss.
待会见
See you later.
好吧
All right.
纽约皇后区  1970年6月11日
欢迎你回来
Welcome home, Batts.
近来好吗?
Hi, how are you?
坐下  喝一杯  给每个人一杯酒
Sit down. Have a drink. Give them all a drink.
那些爱尔兰流氓  也给他们一杯
And give those Irish hoodlums a drink.
只有一个爱尔兰人
There's only one Irishman here.
这是庆祝会  干杯
It's a celebration, fellas.
- 祝你早安  - 从牢里回来真好
- Top of the morning to you. - It's good to be home.
这是我朋友吉米
This is my friend Jimmy.
这里是亨利的店  这是莉莎
Henry. It's his joint. This is Lisa.
汤米  这么盛装呀
Tommy. All dressed up.
已经是大人了  你看看
All grown up and doing the town. Look at this.
忘了你们在替他庆祝
Forgot you were having a party for this mug.
过来呀
Come here.
我过去打个招呼  比利  你好吗
I'll say hello. Billy, how are you?
我已经六年没见你了
Get over here. I haven't seen you in six years.
上帝  你看起来真神气
Jesus Christ Almighty. You look terrific.
当心我的西装
Watch the suit.
你这小混球  我认识你一辈子了
You little prick. I've known you all my life.
- 不要长得太大了  - 你不要找我麻烦就好了
- Don't get too big on me. - Just don't bust my balls.
如果我要找你麻烦  我会叫你回去拿擦鞋盒来
If I was gonna break your balls, I'd say, "Go get your shine box."
这小鬼以前鞋擦得真亮
This kid was great.
他外号叫  亮光汤米
They used to call him "Spitshine Tommy."
他妈的简直像镜子一样  语气稍粗了  抱歉
He'd make your shoes look like fucking mirrors. Excuse my language.
他真赚了不少钱
He was terrific. He was the best. He made a lot of money, too.
不要再提擦鞋了  比利
No more shines, Billy.
- 什么  - 我说不要再提擦鞋了
- What? - I said no more shines.
你离开了很长一段时间  他们没告诉你
You've been away a long time. They didn't tell you.
我不擦鞋了
I don't shine shoes anymore.
不要这么认真好不好  只是好玩的  给你找点小麻烦而已
Relax. What's got into you? I'm breaking your balls a little, that's all.
我只是逗着你玩的
I'm only kidding with you.
有时你的语气不像在玩  这里有很多人  你知道吗
Sometimes you don't sound like it. There's a lot of people around.
我只是跟你开玩笑  我们在庆祝
I'm only kidding. We're having a party.
我好久没见你  只想逗逗你  你马上就变脸了
I haven't seen you in a long time and you get fucking fresh.
对不起  我不是故意想惹你生气
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to offend you.
抱歉  没事了  好了
I'm sorry, too. It's okay. No problem.
回去把你的擦鞋箱拿来
Now go home and get your fucking shine box.
你他妈的不是人养的
Motherfucking mutt!
你这摊大便
You fucking piece of shit!
来呀  来呀
Come on, come on!
谁不知道你用钱买到你在帮中的地位  假狠
He bought his fucking button! That fake old tough guy!
谁不知道你用钱买到你在帮中的地位
You bought your fucking button!
- 别紧张  - 你这个蓄生
- Don't get nervous. - You motherfucker!
把这王八蛋留在这里
Keep that motherfucker here! Keep him here.
来呀  你以为你很强吗
Come on, you fucking feel strong?
汤米喝太多了  他并没恶意
Sorry. Tommy gets a little loaded. He doesn't mean any disrespect.
他没有恶意  你疯啦
He doesn't mean any disrespect? Are you nuts?
应该教这小子一点礼貌  对就是对
Teach this kid a little fucking manners. What's right is right.
- 你知道我的意思吧  - 没关系
- You understand what I'm saying? - It's all right.
我是说那小子两分钟前还跟我行贴面礼  一转脸就六亲不认了
We're hugging and kissing over here and then he acts like a fucking jerk.
那是因为你讽刺他  你自己也有不对
You insulted him a little bit. You got a little out of order.
- 哪有  - 你有一点讽刺他
- I didn't. - You insulted him a little.
- 我没讽刺任何人  给我们来酒  - 好的
- I didn't insult anybody. Give us a drink. - Okay.
我们都来一杯吧  我请客
Let's have some drinks. Drinks on the house.
不  由我来请
No, have the drink with me.
比利  酒免费
The drinks are on the house.
我在牢里都强奸那种小子
I fucked kids like that in the can. In the ass.
他妈的  敢破坏我的庆祝会
Fucking break up my party.
时代变了  你离开六年了
You've been away for six years. It's different now.
我已经被惩罚过了
I did my fucking time, Jimmy.
我回来了  我要我该有的一份  我得养家糊口
I came home and I want what I got to get. I got mouths to feed.
- 你会得到的  - 你能了解吧
- You're gonna get it. - You understand?
关上门
Get the door!
让我把子弹射进他的大烂嘴巴
Let me shoot him in his big, fucking mouth!
枪毙了他
Let's shoot him.
死家伙把我鞋弄凹了
Fucking mutt dented my shoes.
他手下的人会到处找他的
His whole crew is going to be looking for him.
真糟糕  怎么处理他  总不能把他丢在街上
This is bad. What do we do with him? We can't just dump him on the street.
我知道郊外有个地方  谁也找不到  再拿几张桌布
I know a place upstate. They'll never find him. More tablecloths.
我本来不想把血溅在你地板上
I didn't want to get blood on your floor.
去把你的车厢打开
Go open your trunk.
到我妈妈家去拿一把铲子
We'll get a shovel at my mother's house.
她有一把铲子就放在附近  小声一点  别把她吵醒
She has a shovel here somewhere. Quiet, I don't want to wake her up.
看谁来了
Look who's here.
你们刚才在做什么  发生了什么事
What did you do? What happened?
我在路上撞了一只动物  吉米会告诉你
I hit something on the road. Jimmy will tell you.
发生什么事了
What happened to him?
我好久没看到你了  他怎么啦
I haven't seen you in so long. What happened to him?
你好吗
You, too. How are you?
你怎么这么晚还不睡
Why are you up so late?
他来了  你们都来了  我好高兴看到他
He came in. You came in. I'm so happy to see him.
快进来吧  不要客气  我给你们弄点吃的
Go inside. Make yourselves comfortable. I'll make you something to eat.
- 你去睡吧  - 我睡不着  我好久没看到他了
- Go to sleep. We're leaving. - I can't. Not while he's home.
我好久没看到他了  我想陪陪他
I haven't seen him in so long. I want to see him.
你们进去吧
You go inside.
This stuff is like lead.
告诉我  你去哪里了  我都没看见你
Tell me, where you been? I haven't seen you.
也不打个电话回来  你都去哪了
You haven't called. Where have you been?
- 我在上夜班  - 然后呢
- I been working nights. - And?
今晚我们开车到郊外溜达
And tonight we were out late.
撞上一只鹿
We took a ride out to the country and hit a deer.
所以才有这些血  吉米不也告诉你了吗
That's where all the blood is from. Jimmy told you.
对了  我要借这把刀用一下  好吗
It reminds me, I need this knife. I'm taking this, okay?
- 用吧  - 我只需要用一下就好
- Okay. - Just for a while.
可怜的鹿
The poor thing.
我们撞到那只鹿的  那个  那个叫什么
We hit the deer and his paw... What do you call it?
前爪
The paw.
- 鹿蹄  - 他前蹄被卡住了
- The hoof. - Got caught in the grill.
我必须把它切下来
I got to hack it off.
如果不管它  那太不人道了
Ma, it's a sin to leave it there.
刀用完我就送回来
I'll bring the knife back.
- 真好吃  美味  - 谢谢你
- Delicious. - Thank you.
你为什么不找个好姑娘
Why don't you get yourself a nice girl?
我每天晚上都找好姑娘
I do, almost every night.
我是说找个好女孩  能结婚安定下来
But get yourself a girl so you could settle down.
我每晚都安定下来  然后早上又自由了
I do, every night. Then I'm free.
我爱你  只想和你在一起
I love you, I want to be with you.
安定一下自己啦
Settle down.
亨利怎么样呀
How's your friend Henry?
怎么了  你不怎么讲话
What's the matter? You don't talk much.
对啊  这么安静做什么
Talk. What are you quiet for?
他吃得少  说话也少
You don't eat much, you don't talk much.
- 我听着就好了  - 有什么不对劲吗
- I'm just listening. - Something wrong?
你让我想起我们小的时候  从意大利来的人都很亲近
When we were kids, the compares used to visit each other.
有一个人从来不说话  他整晚坐着一句话都不说
There was this man. He would never talk. He'd just sit there all night, not a word.
有人问他  你哪里不对劲呀  你会不会说话
They say to him, "What's the matter? Don't you say anything?"
他说  你要我说什么  说我老婆爱偷情
He says, "What am I going to say, that my wife two-times me?"
他老婆说  闭嘴  你话太多了
So she says, "Shut up! You're always talking."
不过这句话用意大利语说出来好听多了
But in Italian, it sounds much nicer.
- 自得其乐  - 就是 满于现况 的意思
- Cornuto contento. - That's it.
- 什么意思呀  - 就是连那样他都满足
- What does that mean? - It means he's content to be a jerk.
别人怎么想  他才不在乎
He doesn't care who knows it.
- 汤米有没有告诉你们我画画  - 没有
- Did Tommy tell you about my painting? - No.
看看这个
Look at this.
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
一只狗脸朝这边  另一只脸朝那边
I like it. One dog goes one way and the other goes the other.
一只想到东部  一只想到西部  又怎样咧
One's facing east, the other west. So what?
这人在说  你要我怎么样  他那头白发挺漂亮的
He's saying, "What do you want from me?" The guy's got nice white hair.
漂亮  那只狗  看起来差不多
Beautiful. The dog looks the same.
这个人有点像我们认识的一个人
Looks like somebody we know.
去掉胡子不就是他吗
Without the beard. It's him.
就是他
It's him.
妈的  什么声音啊
What the fuck is that?
对大部分兄弟来说  杀人是被接受的
For most of the guys, killings were accepted.
要令每个人服从  只有用处决来控制
Murder was the only way everybody stayed in line.
你如果越轨就会被除掉  规则大家都知道
You got out of line, you got whacked. Everybody knew the rules.
有时候没越轨也会被除掉
Sometimes, even if people didn't get out of line, they got whacked.
有些兄弟已是杀人成性  动不动就挑衅
Hits became a habit. Guys would get into arguments over nothing.
时常  转眼就死了一个人
Before you knew it, one was dead.
彼此常以枪相对
They were shooting each other all the time.
早已习以为常  不值得大惊小怪
Shooting people was a normal thing. It was no big deal.
我们跟比利·贝兹的事可不是件小事情
We had a serious problem with Billy Batts.
汤米杀的是个大人物  地位很高的
This was really a touchy thing. Tommy killed a made guy.
贝兹是坎必诺家族的一员  这种人是不能随便杀的
Batts was part of the Gambino crew and was considered untouchable.
你得有充分的理由
Before you touched a made guy, you had to have a good reason.
你得有上面正式的许可
You had to have a sit-down and you'd better get an okay...
否则  被杀的人就是你
or you'd be the one who got whacked.
星期六是太太之夜
Saturday night was for wives...
礼拜五是女朋友之夜
but Friday night at the Copa was for the girlfriends.
上星期我们看了山米·戴维斯的秀
Last week, we saw Sammy Davis, Jr.
太值得看了  好会表演
You got to see this show. What a performer.
他会模仿别人  听起来就跟真人一样
He does these impersonations. You'd think it was the real people.
真令人难以相信  难怪白人女孩为他倾心
It's unbelievable. You could see how a white girl could fall for him.
什么
What?
我不是说我  只是有的女孩  像那个瑞典女孩
Not me. But you could see how some girls could. Like that Swedish girl.
换句话说  你赞同那种黑白关系
So you condone that stuff.
别那么认真
Take it easy.
我不要间接跟黑人接吻
I don't want to be kissing Nat King Cole over here.
我又不是在说我自己
No, I'm not talking about me.
他很有个性
But, you know, he's got personality.
个性
Personality?
他非常有才气  我完全明白
He's talented. I understand what you're saying.
不过你要注意你所说的话  别人很容易误会
But watch what you say. People get the wrong impression.
我只是说他很有才气  令人难以相信
I just said he was talented, you're unbelievable.
你说够了吧  你说的我都懂
Just leave it alone now, I understand what you said.
他很有才气  就这样子
He's talented. Leave it at that.
连给保利叔叔亲一下都不行
No? Not even Uncle Paulie?
你有没有听到什么消息
What did you hear about that thing?
- 布鲁克林的事吗  - 不是  城中那家伙的事
- The Brooklyn thing? - No, the guy from downtown.
- 克莉丝家附近那家伙吗  - 不是
- The guy from where Christie lived? - No.
失踪的那个家伙  也就是曾经被警察逮捕定罪的那个家伙
The guy who disappeared, the one they made the beef on.
- 你认得那个人吗  - 是呀
- Know the guy I mean? - Yeah.
他叫贝兹  他手下的人像疯了一样到处找他
His name was Batts. His people are driving everyone crazy looking for him.
没人知道他去哪里了
Nobody knows what happened to him.
有天晚上他到我店来过  他走之后就失踪了
He came into the joint that night and then just disappeared. That was it.
好  眼睛放亮一点  他们一直来跟我啰嗦
All right. Keep your eyes open. They're busting my balls over it.
- 好吗  - 我会的
- All right? - Yeah.
好吧  大家来吃吧
Okay, everybody, let's eat.
我要我的钱
I want my money.
他欠我
He owes it.
还记得郊外那件事吗
You know that thing we took care of upstate?
- 保利刚才还提到呢  - 我们得把他挖出来
- Paulie was talking about that. - Got to get it out of there.
那块地就要开始建大厦了
They just sold the property to make condominiums.
- 已经六个月了呀  - 我们要马上把他移走
- It's been six months. - We got to get it out of there right away.
亨利  快点好不好  我妈要给我们炸香肠吃
Henry, hurry up. My mother's making fried peppers and sausage for us.
- 这有只手臂  - 很好笑呀
- Here's an arm. - Very funny, guys.
这儿有条腿
Here's a leg.
这儿有只翅膀
Here's a wing.
你喜欢什么  大腿还是翅膀  心还是肺
What do you like, the leg or the wing? Or you still go for the hearts and lungs?
真臭死了
Oh, that's so bad.
车子怎么了
What happened to the car?
我撞死了一只臭鼬
I hit a skunk, all right?
跟妈妈走吧
Go with your mother.
真是恶心死了  亨利
It's disgusting, Henry.
我把珍丽丝安顿在离家不远的公寓里
I set up Janice in an apartment around the corner from The Suite.
那样我每星期可以在她那儿过夜一两次
That way I was able to stay over a couple of nights a week.
这是新买的古董台灯
This is my new antique lamp.
凯伦从来不过问我的事  她只在家里带孩子
Karen was home with the kids. She never asked questions.
家具都是设计家摩瑞斯的作品
The furniture's all Maurice Valencia.
好像是罗马的作品
Looks like Roma.
这些都是真丝的  从暹罗进口的
This is all silk. This is from Siam.
来看我的卧房
Come see my bedroom.
- 汤米  你抱他一下好吗  - 我今晚就把他吃掉
- Tommy, will you take him? - I'll eat this fucking dog tonight.
喜欢那个水晶球吗
Love that crystal ball or what?
我们多数时间都是在这里消磨的
This is where we spend most of our time.
那盆花插得真美
I love the floral arrangements.
法国货呀
French.
珍丽丝只顾和我一起玩乐  工作上出轨了
Janice and I were having so much fun, she started screwing up at work.
我只好去给她老板一点教训
I had to straighten out her boss a little bit.
珍丽丝喜欢怎么做  她就可以怎么做  你懂吗
Janice can do what she wants to do. Got it?
随便你往哪里跑  如果你再挂我的电话  你试试看
Just try to run. Hang up once more, and you'll deal with me.
好了啦  放开她
Come on, get off of her.
你真是个野兽
You're an animal.
小蜘蛛  过来带杯酒给我
Spider, on your way over here, bring me a Cutty and water.
- 你们吃饭了没有  - 我饿死了
- Did you guys eat? - I'm starving.
- 打就打啦  - 那些你也能打
- I'll play these. - You'll play those?
我有口吃吗  那些我都打
Do I stutter? I play those.
我是什么  我不存在呀
What am I? A mirage?
什么  我的酒呢
Where's my fucking drink? I asked you for a drink.
- 你有说要酒吗  - 我刚才跟你说要酒呀
- You wanted a drink? - I asked you for one.
我以为你是说  我不用了  小蜘蛛
I thought you said, "I'm all right, Spider."
你把我例入不用理会的名单吗
Am I on a pay-no-mind list?
不是的  我听到有人叫  小蜘蛛  小蜘蛛
No, I heard someone say "Spider, Spider."
- 我以为是亨利在叫吧  - 你简直是又笨又口吃的蠢货
- I thought it was Henry. - You're a mumbling, stuttering little fuck.
我以为你说  我不用了  小蜘蛛
I thought you said, "I'm all right, Spider."
你麻烦大了
You ain't all right.
我真的以为你说  没事了
No, I thought you said you were all right.
我是没事  你就有事了
I am all right! You ain't, you prick.
你说了一晚上了  小王八蛋
You've been doing this all fucking night to me, you motherfucker!
你现在要不要酒  我去给你拿
He wants a drink now? I'll bring it.
去给我倒酒  快点呀  你个小混球
Go get me a fucking drink! Move it, you little prick.
你走路好像史帝芬·费区一样慢
You walk like fucking Stepin Fetchit.
为我跑快点行不行
For everybody else you run.
一面跳舞一面抱酒拿过来!
Run for me, you prick! Dance, dance the fucking drink back here!
像鲍嘉在什么电影里一样
What's that movie that Bogart made?
- 就是他扮牛仔那部  - 奥克拉荷马小子
- Where he played a cowboy. - The Oklahoma Kid.
- 奥克拉荷马小子  史恩  - 我就是奥克拉荷马小子
- Shane? - Oklahoma Kid, that's me!
你这没用的东西  跳舞呀
You fucking varmint. Dance!
你这混蛋
Yahoo, you motherfucker!
把小孩和妇女藏妥
Round up those fucking wagons.
现在他动作可快了
Now he's moving.
- 亨利  怎么样了  - 你打中他的脚了  汤米
- Henry, what happened? - He shot him in the foot, Tommy.
他没事啦  脚被射中了又怎样  算是件大事吗  是不是
He's fucking fine. So he got shot in the foot. What is it? A big fucking deal?
- 维多  拿条毛巾来  - 玩得好
- Get a towel. - Nice fucking game.
带他去看宝凯西医生吧
Take him to Ben Casey, the little prick.
让他爬去  就像他拿酒的时候一样慢慢爬
Let him crawl like he crawls for the drinks.
带他去看街口那个医生
Take him to the doctor down the street.
我的脚骨头全碎了
Bones are all shattered.
不要再惹我生气了
Don't get me upset, now.
没什么大不了的  小蜘蛛  你这小混球
Don't make a big fucking thing out of it, Spider, you little prick.
你们想要我为这件事抱歉吗
You trying to make me think what the fuck I did here.
那只是件意外而已
It was an accident.
- 别演戏了  小子  - 我这手牌很不错
- Little fucking actor. - I got a great hand here.
- 这一手你跟不跟呀  - 跟了
- You in or out? - Yeah, I'm in.
- 800元  - 800元
- $800. - $800?
你已经两星期没回家了  今天晚上不准出去!
You haven't been home in two weeks. You're not going out tonight!
凯伦  别孩子气好不好  我还是要出去的
Karen, will you grow up! Stop! I'm still gonna go out!
车钥匙不给你  你去呀
Not without your car keys, you're not.
你疯啦  是不是
Are you nuts? What's your problem?
是  我是疯了  你在玩什么花样
Yes, I'm nuts. Something's going on.
- 别说了  够了  不要说了  - 不好
- Stop with that. Enough! Stop with that. - No!
我告诉你  我看你的脸  就知道你在说谎
I'm telling you, I look in your face and I know that you're lying!
- 滚出去  - 闭嘴
- Get out! Get out! - Shut up.
滚出我的生活
Get out of my life!
你昏头了  一切都是你想象出来的
You're fucked in the head, Karen. This is all in your mind.
- 你是个低级的混蛋  - 你脑子有问题
- You're a lousy bastard! - You got a problem.
去呀  去找你的现成妓女呀  你只配找那种女人
Go ahead, go to your ready-made whores. That's all you're good for!
滚出我的生活  我不能忍受你了
Get out of my life! I can't stand you!
小蜘蛛  急什么嘛
Spider, what's your rush?
- 给你  - 谢谢你  小蜘蛛
- Here you go. - Thank you, Spider.
小蜘蛛  你脚上的纱布包得比你的头还大
Spider, that fucking bandage on your foot is bigger than your fucking head.
下一次他就要用手杖来走路了
Next thing you know, he's gonna be coming in one of these fucking walkers.
虽然你脚受伤了  你还是可以跳舞吧
Even though you got that, you can dance?
给我们表演几步  你这个装模作样的混球
Give us a couple of fucking steps, Spider. You fucking bullshitter, you.
说实话吧  你是希望大家同情你
Tell the truth. You're looking for sympathy?
你去操你自己吧  汤米
Why don't you go fuck yourself, Tommy?
我不相信我所听到的
I didn't fucking hear right. Can't believe what I heard.
小蜘蛛  这个给你  有种
Spider, here. This is for you. Attaboy.
我看得起这小子  有勇气
I got respect for this kid. He's got a lot of fucking balls.
不吃任何人这一套
Good for you. Don't take no shit off nobody.
他打中他的脚  他叫他去操自己
He shoots him in the foot, he tells him to go fuck himself.
你就让这小混球这样骂你
Are you gonna let this fucking punk get away with that?
你怎么回事呀  这成什么世界啦
What's the matter? What's the world coming to?
就成这样的世界  你认为如何
That's what the fucking world is coming to. How do you like that?
- 行了吧  - 你发疯啦你
- How's that, all right? - What's the fucking matter with you?
你是笨蛋还是什么
What are you, stupid or what?
汤米  我是在跟你开玩笑  你是神经不正常了是不是
Tommy, I'm kidding with you. Are you a fucking sick maniac?
我怎么知道你是开玩笑  你是在糗我
How do I know if you're kidding? You're breaking my fucking balls?
我在开你的玩笑  你却开枪
I'm fucking kidding with you, you fucking shoot the guy?
他死了
He's dead.
射得真准  你要我怎么办嘛  我就是准
Good shot. I'm a lucky man. Good shot.
这种距离会射不准吗
You can't miss at this distance.
怎么  你有什么意见吗
You got a problem with what I did, Anthony?
没有
No.
反正是个烂人  他全家都是告密者
Fucking rat. His whole family's all rats. He would've grown up to be a rat.
真是蠢到极点了  我真不敢相信你会做这种事
Stupid bastard! I can't fucking believe you.
你自己去挖坑吧  我没法处理
Now you're going to dig the hole. I got no fucking lime.
谁在乎  我自己会挖坑  这又不是我第一次挖坑
I'll dig the hole. I don't give a fuck. Is it the first hole I dug?
我去挖就是了  铲子在哪
I'll dig the fucking hole. Where are the shovels?
- 哈罗  - 哈罗
- Hello. - Hello?
这是凯伦·希尔  我要跟你谈谈
This is Karen Hill. I wanna talk to you.
哈罗  不要挂上
Hello? Don't hang up on me!
我要和你说话
I want to talk to you!
你离我丈夫远一点  听见没有
You keep away from my husband, you hear me?
哈罗  把门打开
Hello? Open the door!
回答我
Answer me!
我要告诉每一个走进大楼的人
I'm gonna tell everyone who walks in this building...
住在2R的罗茜是妓女
that in 2R, Rossi, you are nothing but a whore!
是不是管理员
Is this the superintendent?
我是要告诉你  有个妓女
Yes, I want you to know, sir, that you have a whore...
住在你大厦的2R房间
living in 2R!
罗茜  珍丽丝·罗茜  你听见了吗
Rossi, Janice Rossi. Do you hear me?
他是我丈夫
He's my husband!
有本事自己找个男人
Get your own goddamn man!
醒醒  亨利
Wake up, Henry.
- 凯伦  你疯啦  - 我是疯了
- Karen, are you crazy? - I am crazy.
疯得足以杀掉你们
I'm crazy enough to kill both of you.
凯伦  别动气好不好
Karen, take it easy.
- 好不好  - 你爱不爱她
- Okay? - Do you love her?
爱不爱
Do you?
- 爱不爱  - 凯伦
- Do you? - Karen...
我爱你  你知道我爱你的
I love you. You know I love you.
你不爱我
You don't.
不  你不爱我
No, you don't.
当心点  凯伦  求求你
Please, be careful. Baby, don't.
我还是没办法伤害他
But still I couldn't hurt him. How could I hurt him?
我连离开他的勇气都没有
I couldn't even bring myself to leave him.
说实在的
The truth was...
不管我再怎么生气
that no matter how bad I felt...
他对我还是有吸引力
I was still very attracted to him.
我为什么要拱手把他让给她呢
Why should I give him to someone else?
谁说要她赢我输
Why should she win?
把枪放下来
Just put it down.
你知道我是爱你的  不是吗
You know I love you, don't you?
我全心全意只要你
You're all I want, Karen.
凯伦  请把枪放下来
Please put the gun down, Karen.
拜托啦  宝贝
Baby, come on.
你是疯了是不是  凯伦
What are you, fucking crazy, Karen?
外面的事就够叫我提心吊胆的了
I got enough to worry about getting whacked on the street!
我回来还要面对这个
I got to fucking come home for this?
我真该杀了你
I should fucking kill you!
这是什么滋味
How does it feel?
这是什么滋味  凯伦
How does it feel, Karen?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry!
吉米  你好吗
Hi, Jimmy! How are you?
- 看来挺好嘛  - 谢谢  很高兴见到你
- Looking good. - Thank you. Good to see you.
- 保利  - 甜心  你好吧
- Hi, Paulie! - Hi, honey. How are you?
很好呀
Good.
- 你去帮我买包香烟好吗  - 好
- Why don't you go get cigarettes, okay? - Sure.
- 你们需要什么吗  - 不用
- Any of you need anything? - I'm all right.
- 你们要喝什么吗  啤酒  - 不用
- Want anything to drink? A beer? - No.
- 来点中国菜  - 不用  过来坐下
- Chinese food? - No, come on, sit down.
凯伦来看我了
Karen came to the house.
她很气愤
She's very upset.
这样很不好  你要把你们的问题解决一下
This is no good. You gotta straighten this thing out.
我们一定要冷静  她什么事都做得出来
We got to have calm now. We don't know what the hell she's gonna do.
她已经歇斯底里了  很容易兴奋
She's getting all hysterical. She gets very excited.
她很激动  你就得慢慢来  别忘了还有孩子
She's wild. And you got to take it easy. You got children.
我不是说要你马上回去  不过你还是非回去不可
I'm not saying you gotta back to her this minute, but you gotta go back.
你别无选择  你得注意自己的形象
It's the only way. You gotta keep up appearances.
凯伦跟美琪每天到我家来诉苦
The two of them come over every day, commiserating.
我受不了了
I can't have it.
亨利  我不能那样
I can't do it, Henry.
没人说你不能做你喜欢的
Nobody says that you can't do what you wanna do.
我们知道是怎么回事
We all know that. I mean, this is what it is.
可是你要面面俱到
We know what it is. You have to do the right thing.
你不能不顾到你的家庭  懂吗
You have to go home to the family, you understand?
你就是得回家  知道吗
You got to go home, okay? Look at me.
你就是得回家  放聪明一点
You gotta go home. Smarten up.
- 好吗  - 好吧
- All right? - All right.
我会跟凯伦讲讲
I'm gonna talk to Karen.
我会把事摆平  我知道该对她说些什么
I'll straighten this out. I know just what to say to her.
我会说你愿意回去
I'm gonna tell her you'll go back to her...
一切跟以前一样
and it'll be just the way it was when you were first married...
我会说得很动人  会很圆满的
your romance, it's gonna be beautiful.
跟她谈  我很有把握
I know how to talk to her, especially to her.
吉米跟汤米要到天波城
Jimmy and Tommy are going down to Tampa this weekend...
去帮我拿东西
to pick up something for me.
你代替汤米和吉米去好了
Instead, you go with Jimmy.
你来和我一起去吧
You come with me, we'll go down.
好好玩玩  让自己轻松一下
Have a good time. Take some time for yourself. Relax.
在太阳底下好好休息
Sit in the sun. Take a couple days off.
- 我们会玩得很愉快的  - 好好玩
- We'll have a good time. - Enjoy yourselves.
但当你回来时  你就要回到凯伦身边
And when you come back, you go back to Karen.
拜托你了  别无他法
Please, there's no other way.
你不能离婚  我们不是禽兽
You're not gonna get a divorce. We're not animali.
他们不会离婚  她永远不会同意离婚
No divorce. She'll never divorce him.
她会杀了他  但不会跟他离婚
She'll kill him, but she won't divorce him.
你到底付不付
You gonna pay us?
佛罗里达州天波市  两天后
- 你付钱呀  - 快把钱给我们
- You gonna pay? - Give us the fucking money!
我没有  我真的没有
I can't, I swear.
我们走
Let's go.
天波市立动物园
- 我们把这个杂种丢给狮子  - 不要呀
- We'll throw the bastard to the lions. - No!
什么狮子  我可不要进去  吉米
What fucking lions? I ain't going near any lions, Jimmy!
- 把他丢过分界沟就行了  - 那好
- Let's throw him over the moat. - All right.
我一定把钱给你们
I'll get the money!
一定要有人被喂狮子
They must really feed each other to the lions down there...
那家伙马上就付钱了
because the guy gave the money right up.
我对上帝发誓我会付钱
I swear to Christ, I'll get the money.
我们在赛马场度周末
We got to spend the rest of the weekend at the track.
他们不是开玩笑的
Yeah. They mean business.
接着发生的真的难以相信
Then, I couldn't believe what happened.
当我们回到家的时候  我们已经是新闻人物了
When we got home, we were all over the newspaper.
最初  我根本不知道那边会跟媒体有牵连
At first, I didn't even know why we got picked up.
后来才知道被我们揍的人的姐姐
Then I found out that the guy we roughed up...
是FBI打字员
turned out to have a sister working as a typist for the FBI.
谁会想到天下有那么巧的事
Who could believe it? Of all the fucking people.
她把吉米  我  甚至她弟弟全都抖出来了
She gave up everybody: Jimmy, me, even her brother.
陪审团花了六小时  裁决我们有罪
It took the jury six hours to bring us in guilty.
法官判我和吉米每人十年  好像在发糖果一样
The judge gave Jimmy and me 10 years like he was giving away candy.
判处你们在国立监狱服刑十年
...ten years in a federal penitentiary.
现在交给检察官
You will now be turned over to the U.S. Attorney General's office.
来敬你一杯
Toast, guys.
一路平安  祝福你们早日出来
Good trip, good life, get out soon.
一切顺利
Good trip, sweetheart.
我们会替你照顾家的
We'll watch the home front.
替我问候那些口交的警卫
Say hello to those blow-job hacks.
别忘了一有机会就占他们的便宜
Yeah, motherfuck them every chance you get.
有机会我会打电话给你
I'll call you when I get a chance.
送我去监狱吧
Now take me to jail.
在监狱里  晚餐很重要
In prison, dinner was always a big thing.
先来一道意大利面  接着或鱼或肉
We had a pasta course, and then we had a meat or a fish.
保利因藐视法庭被判了一年  他负责准备工作
Paulie did the prep work. He was doing a year for contempt...
他有一套切大蒜的诀窍
and had this wonderful system for doing the garlic.
用刀片切得很薄
He used a razor, and he used to slice it so thin...
放在锅里  加上一点油就化了
that it used to liquefy in the pan with just a little oil.
那方法很好
It was a very good system.
韦力掌管蕃茄汁
Vinnie was in charge of the tomato sauce.
闻到了没有
Get the smell?
这肉丸里有三种肉
Three kinds of meat in the meatballs:
有小牛肉  牛肉和猪肉
Veal, beef, and pork.
那好  反正猪肉是一定要的
Good, but you gotta have the pork.
那是主要的味道来源
That's the flavor.
我觉得他洋葱放多了  但味道还是很好
I felt he used too many onions, but it was still a very good sauce.
韦力  不要放太多洋葱
Vinnie, don't put too many onions in the sauce.
我没放太多
I didn't put too much onions in, Paul.
只放了三个小的而已
Put three small onions, that's all I did.
三个洋葱  那你放了几罐蕃茄酱
Three onions? How many cans of tomatoes you put in there?
- 两大罐  - 你不需要放三个洋葱
- I put two big cans. - You don't need three onions.
强尼煎牛排
Johnny Dio did the meat.
因为没有烤箱  强尼用平底锅做菜
We had no broiler, so Johnny did everything in pans.
他每次都把屋子里弄得乌烟瘴气
It used to smell up the joint something awful...
警卫都被熏死了  但他的牛排还真是不错
and the hacks used to die, but he still cooked a great steak.
- 你的牛排要怎么样  - 半生的
- How do you like yours? - Medium rare.
半生  贵族一个
Medium rare. An aristocrat.
当你想到监狱  脑中就会出现像电影中那样
You know, when you think of prison you get pictures in your mind...
一排排的人被关在铁栏杆后面
of all those old movies with rows of guys behind bars.
对兄弟来说不是那样的
It wasn't like that for wiseguys.
并不是那么槽  除了我很想念吉米
It really wasn't that bad, excepting that I missed Jimmy...
他在亚特兰大受刑
who was doing his time in Atlanta.
顺便给我两块牛排  好不好
Give me two steaks while you're in there, all right?
在里面的人都是严格地在受刑  混在一起像猪一样
Everyone else in the joint was doing real time, mixed together, living like pigs.
可是我们单独生活  一切都由我们控制
But we lived alone. We owned the joint.
用球棒把那两个狗娘养的脸打烂了  认都认不出来
We batted them sons of bitches. You couldn't recognize them.
太好了  活该
Good, they deserved it.
虽然有些警卫不受贿  但他们也不会告发我们
Even the hacks we couldn't bribe would never rat on the guys we did.
这样才对  朋友邻居间应该互相尊重
...had respect. People loved one another.
夜不闭户
They left their doors open.
抱歉  久等了
Sorry it took so long.
那个瘦子警卫越来越令人讨厌了
The skinny guard's getting to be a real pain in the ass.
- 是该给那个杂种一点教训了  - 我已经摆平了
- We're gonna have to do something. - I took care of him.
你带了些什么来
What'd you bring?
- 面包  - 好
- Bread. - Good.
- 才烤出来的  - 韦力  你的辣椒和洋葱有了
- Fresh. - Vinnie, I got your peppers and onions.
香肠  火腿  还有很多奶酪
Salami, prosciutto, a lot of cheese.
还有呢  还有什么别的
Come on, what else?
- 威士忌  - 好
- Scotch. - Nice.
- 红酒  - 好了
- Some red wine. - Okay.
- 我们可以吃了  - 我也拿了白葡萄酒
- Now we can eat. - I got some white, too.
白葡萄酒也给我  太美了
Give me the white, too. Beautiful.
来吧  伙计们  我们可以吃了  已经好了  韦力
Okay, boys, let's eat. Come on, it's ready, Vinnie.
这里还有些面包
Some more bread.
明天我们吃三明治  你该节食了  韦力
Tomorrow we eat sandwiches. You got to go on a diet, Vinnie.
- 你别开玩笑了  - 你最好听我的
- You must be kidding. - Believe me.
你在忙什么
What are you doing?
我也来一点
I'll take that.
- 好  晚一点见  - 对
- All right, I'll catch you guys later. - Yeah.
去公园散散步  是不是
You going for a walk in the park?
- 好  下礼拜见  谢谢  - 好
- Okay, I'll catch you next week. Thanks. - Okay.
- 还有没有  - 没了  全光了  周末愉快
- Is there any more? - No, that's it. Have a good weekend.
- 谢啦  - 亨利  再见了
- Thanks. - You too, Henry.
来
Come on.
好好站在这儿
You girls stay right here.
- 你们两个牵着手  - 好了  一直走到前面去
- I want you to hold hands. - Okay, go right up to the front.
- 走吧  - 你好吗
- Let's go. - How you doing?
- 还行  你呢  - 很好  谢谢你
- Good, how are you? - Very well, thank you.
- 你讲什么呀  - 我在登记簿上看到她的名字了
- What you talking about? - I saw her name in the register.
- 老天呀  - 你要她来看你吗
- Jesus Christ. - You want her to visit you?
让她为你哭整晚不睡  还写信给假释管理局
Let her stay up all night crying and writing letters to the parole board.
你以为我在这儿做什么  我在坐牢呀
What am I doing here? Where am I? I'm in jail.
我不能阻止别人来看我呀
I can't stop people from coming to see me.
好呀  让她每星期替你偷运这些东西进来
Good, let her sneak this stuff in for you every week.
- 让她每星期来和那些杂种警卫打交道  - 你这是干什么
- Let her fight these bastards every week! - Look what you're doing! Stop it!
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
让她来替你把这些狗屎运进来
Let her sneak this shit in for you.
你够了没有  凯伦
Will you stop it, Karen?
- 让她去做所有的事嘛  - 够了
- Let her do it! - Stop it!
我好孤独  没有人要帮我
Nobody's helping me. I'm all alone.
贝儿和摩里都破产了
Belle and Morrie are broke.
我向你的朋友利摩讨他欠你的钱
I asked your friend Remo for the money that he owes you.
你知道他说什么吗
You know what he told me?
他叫我把孩子们带到警察局去领救济金
He told me to take my kids down to the police station and get on welfare.
一切会过去的
It's gonna be okay.
就连保利  他出去后我也没见到他  我都没见到他们了
Even Paulie, since he got out, I've never seen him. I never see anybody anymore.
只有我们两个了
It's only you and me. That's what happens when you go away.
我告诉过你  一旦进了牢就孤立了  忘掉所有的人  忘掉保利
I told you that we're on our own. Forget everybody else. Forget Paulie.
他在保释期间是不会帮任何人做任何事的
As long as he's on parole, he doesn't want anybody doing anything.
- 我受不了了  - 你能够忍受  听我说
- I can't do it. - Yes, you can. Listen to me.
你只要不断把东西带来
All I need is for you is to keep bringing me the stuff.
这里有个从匹兹堡来的  他会帮我销货
I got a guy in here from Pittsburgh who'll help me move it.
一个月后我们就安定了
In a month we're gonna be fine.
- 我们不需要别人  - 我害怕
- We won't need anybody. - I'm afraid.
我怕万一保利知道你私下在贩毒
I'm afraid if Paulie finds out...
我不是说了吗  不要担心保利
Don't worry about him.
他并没有帮我们呀  他有没有供应食物给我们
He is not helping us out. Is he putting any food on the table?
我们只有彼此帮助
We've gotta help each other.
我们的行动一定要特别特别小心
We've just gotta be really careful while we do it.
别让我再听到她的名字
I don't want to hear a word about her anymore.
永远不会了
Never.
四年后
爸爸
Daddy!
- 我们好想念你  - 你会待下来吗
- We missed you. - Are you here to stay?
你看到我们的画没有  那张房子和彩虹是我画的
Did you see our pictures? I did the one with the house and rainbow.
太阳是我画的
I did the sun.
我的合唱团两星期后有音乐会  你能来吗
My chorus concert is in two weeks. Are you coming?
喜欢我们的房子吗
Do you like the house?
凯伦  收拾行李  我们要搬家了
Karen, get packed. We're moving out of here.
怎么搬
With what?
不用担心  去找新房子就好了
Don't worry, with what. Just start looking for a new house.
明早我要去匹兹堡  那边有几个人欠我一万五千元
I got to go to Pittsburgh in the morning. Those guys there owe me $15,000.
我们没事了  我都安排好了
We'll be all right. I got things lined up.
匹兹堡  你明天要去向你的假释官报到呀
Pittsburgh? You have to go see your parole officer tomorrow.
凯伦  不要操心了  一切都会没问题的
Don't worry about it. Everything's gonna be fine.
- 谁要去保利伯伯家  - 我
- Who wants to go to Uncle Paulie's? - Me!
你要什么
What do you want?
甜心  让妈妈好好吃饭
Sweetheart, let Mommy eat.
气色不错  牢里有吃得这么好吗
You look good. Did you eat this good in the joint?
不要再搞那些勾当了
I don't want any more of that shit.
什么勾当
What shit?
- 离那些垃圾远一点  - 保利
- Just stay away from the garbage. - Look, Paulie...
你在里面做了我不管  你是身不由己
I'm not talking about what you did inside. You did what you had to do.
我指现在  从现在  从这里开始
I'm talking about now. From now. Here and now.
- 我怎么会搞那些  - 不要把我当傻瓜
- Why would I get into that? - Don't make a jerk out of me.
千万不要
Just don't do it.
现在  我要跟你谈吉米  你要注意他
I want to talk to you about Jimmy. You gotta watch out for him.
他很能赚钱  但他太狂了  太冒险了
He's a good earner, but he's wild, takes too many chances.
我了解吉米  你想我会像他那样冒险吗
I know Jimmy. You think I would take chances like him?
汤米也是个好孩子  但他太疯了
Tommy's a good kid, but he's crazy.
他是个牛仔  他样样都想表现
He's a cowboy. He's got too much to prove.
你不能不自己小心
You gotta watch out for kids like this.
我太清楚他们的个性了  我只利用他们做些事
I know what they are. I only use them for certain things.
我不要像盖比那样被人糟蹋  你明白吗
I ain't gonna get fucked like Gribbs, you understand?
盖比已经70岁了  他将老死狱中  那不是我所要的
Gribbs is 70 years old. The fucking guy's gonna die in prison. I don't need that.
所以我现在警告每一个人  连我儿子在内
So I'm warning everybody. Everybody. Could be my son, could be anybody.
就因为盖比手下的人
Gribbs got 20 years just for saying hello to some fuck...
在他背后贩毒  他被判20年
who was sneaking behind his back, selling junk.
我绝不容许这种事发生在我身上  你懂了吗
I don't need that. That won't happen to me, understand?
你能提早出来  是因为我给你找了份工作
You know you're out early because I got you a job.
我不要整天被条子监视  明白吗
I don't need this heat, you understand that?
如果你看到任何人在贩毒  你一定要来告诉我
You see anybody fucking around with this shit you're gonna tell me, right?
不管是谁
That means anybody.
对不对
All right.
对  当然
Yeah. Of course.
我花了一个星期明查暗访  才把那批匹兹堡货卖掉
Took me about a week of sneaking around before I could unload the Pittsburgh stuff.
不过我着实赚了一大笔
But when I did, it was a real score.
我开始利用珊蒂的家来混合毒品
I started using Sandy's place to mix the stuff.
虽然她吸的比她配的还多
And even with Sandy snorting more than she mixed...
但还是利润极大的生意
I could see that this was a really good business.
第二个礼拜我就赚了一万两千元
I made $12,000 in my second week.
为我的房子付了头期款  事情越来越顺利了
I had a down payment on my house and things were really rolling.
我只要偶尔告诉珊蒂我爱她就好了
All I had to do was every once in a while tell Sandy that I loved her.
这种安排太完美了
But it was perfect, I'm telling you.
只要货是从匹兹堡来的
As long as I kept getting the stuff from Pittsburgh...
保利绝不可能发觉
I knew Paulie would never find out.
几个礼拜之后生意做大了  我一个人处理不了
Within a couple of weeks, it got so big I needed some help.
就把吉米和汤米拉了进来
So I got Jimmy and Tommy to come in with me.
真够棒的
It's fucking great.
康威先生
Mr. Conway.
- 你薪水单带来没有  - 有
- Bring your pay slips? - Yeah.
保释部
兴建工程花了四个半月
Four and a half months of dirt.
- 真好呀  - 撑过来了
- It's so good. - I did it.
- 你喜欢吗  - 真是太棒了
- Do you love it? - It's wonderful.
这个订做的  你坐坐看  贝儿
And this we just had to have made special. Go ahead, sit in it, Belle.
有的坐下去真不舒服
The others you couldn't even sit in.
好了  准备好
Okay, you ready?
看着石壁
Watch the wall with the rock.
电工特别设计的
The electricians did it special. Come on.
来呀  来这边
Come on. All right.
这是进口货  两件组合起来的
This was imported. It came in two pieces. Do you believe what they can do?
不错
It's nice, huh?
亨利  到这边来  你跟吉米商量过了没有
Henry, come over here. Did you and Jimmy talk?
我跟他说过了  他会仔细研究这件事的
I talked to him, and he's looking into everything.
这会让上次法国航空的劫案看起来像儿童故事
This'll make the Air France haul look like goddamn peanuts.
- 小声点  - 你确定他会下手  对吗
- Come on. - He's gonna do it, right?
我不是说了吗  他要好好研究一下
I told you. He'll check everything out.
然后再做决定  没有任何承诺
He's looking into it. We'll see what happens. No promises.
我知道  你知道吗  那儿有好几百万
I know. Do you understand? There's millions in there. And I've been...
我想对这批货下手想得都快吐血了  我栽培这个家伙两年了
bleeding for this caper, been cultivating this son of a bitch for two years.
这家伙欠我两万块  一辈子就一次  我可以退休了
He owes me $20,000. Once in a lifetime. I could retire.
不用再为钱操心  我的好梦就要成真了
No more nut every week. No more bullshit. My dream comes true.
来吧  我们来喝一杯吧
Morrie, let's get a drink.
这就是吉米召集在一起
These are the guys that Jimmy put together for what turned out to be...
犯下美国历史上最大劫案 德航劫案 的一批人
the biggest heist in American history: The Lufthansa heist.
汤米跟卡本负责抓住门口警卫
Tommy and Carbone were gonna grab the outside guard...
逼他开大门
and make him get us in the front door.
法国仔和周佛负责把工作人员集中在一起
Frenchy and Joe Buddha had to round up the workers.
强尼负责把货绑起来  以免触到警铃
Johnny Roastbeef had to keep them all tied up and away from the alarms.
就连史达克也被拉进来了
Even Stacks Edwards got in on it.
他常弹吉他  大家都喜欢他
He used to hang around the lounge and play guitar. Everybody loved Stacks.
他的任务是偷辆大卡车
What he was supposed to do was steal the panel truck...
事后由纽泽西州朋友处理掉
and afterwards compact it by a friend of ours out in Jersey.
只有摩里真的烦死人了
Only Morrie was driving us nuts.
摩里  喝一杯酒  然后闭嘴
Morrie, have a drink and shut up.
因为这次的劫案是他从中拉线的
Just because he set this up, he felt he could bust Jimmy's balls...
摩里就以为他可以向吉米预支是理所当然的事
for an advance on the money we were going to steal.
他并没有什么其他的意思  他就是这样的人
He didn't mean anything by it. That's just the way he was.
我让每个人都替我做事  就连以前的婴儿保姆也在内
I had everybody working for me. Even our old baby-sitter, Lois Byrd.
飞机还稳吧
Did you have a good flight?
我恨匹兹堡  你在哪里找到那些烂人的
I hate Pittsburgh. Where did you find such creeps?
好啦  没那么糟啦
Come on, they're not that bad.
跑这一趟是值得的  对吗
And it's worth it, isn't it?
你上礼拜用的是不是这个婴儿
Is this the same baby you used last week?
不  上次是我姐姐的婴儿  这次是狄娜的
No, that one was my sister's. This is Deirdra's.
打哈欠了
Big yawn.
她长得好像你呀
She looks just like you.
空中小姐也这么说
That's what the stewardess said.
别那么狠好不好  珊蒂
Take it easy, Sandy.
饶了我吧  我们这里有的是呀
Come on, give me a break. You got enough here to go around.
少吸一点  你还有一整天  一次太多就不够用了
You got all day. Just make it last, all right? Take it easy.
- 我得走了  - 你去哪里
- I got to go. - Where are you going?
不要跟我争  你知道我要去办事  操  我的车钥匙呢
Don't start. You know I gotta go do this thing. Fuck, where are my keys?
就在那里
Over there.
真够乱的  像猪窝一样
It's a mess. It's like a pig pen.
洗碗机买来是做什么的
What do you think I got you the dishwasher for?
我讨厌洗碗  弄坏我指甲
I hate doing the dishes. Fucks up my nails.
我不管你讨不讨厌洗碗  你要放聪明点
How could you hate it? You got to be smart.
就凭这些白粉  被抓到了我们就别想出来了
Look at all this powder around here. That could put us away forever.
- 别这么紧张嘛  - 你想干什么
- Loosen up. - What are you doing?
- 我得走了  - 你哪儿也不用去
- You know, I gotta... - You don't have to go anywhere.
让他们等
Make them wait.
今晨黎明前  肯尼迪机场的德国航空货运站被劫
Nobody knows for sure just how much was taken in the daring pre-dawn raid...
没人能确定被劫的数目
at the Lufthansa cargo terminal at Kennedy Airport.
FBI说是两百万  航空警察说四百万
The FBI says $2 million, Port Authority Police say $4 million...
吉米
Jimmy!
你们这些狗娘养的
Those sons of bitches!
在肯尼迪机场被劫的现场转播
...from the scene of the heist at JFK.
看起来也许是本市历年来最大的一宗劫案
It looks like a big one. Maybe the biggest this town has ever seen.
过来  过来
Come here, you! Come here!
看看这个天才  这是个天才
Look at this genius. This genius!
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
- 哈罗  这是谁呀  - 这是我太太
- Hello, who's this? - That's my wife.
你过来  给你看一样东西
Come here. I want to show you something, Jimmy.
它美吧
Isn't she gorgeous?
我买给我老婆的  是两门的  我爱死它了
I bought it for my wife. It's a coupe. I love that car.
我怎么跟你说的  我确实跟你说过的
What did I tell you? I talked to you before, didn't I?
你不了解情况吗
Didn't I say what was going on?
我没告诉你暂时不要买东西吗
Didn't I say not to go buy anything for a while?
- 竟然买辆新车  - 是我妈送的
- The fucking car? - It's a wedding gift from my mother.
车主也是她  我才刚结婚呀
It's under her name. I just got married.
- 我好爱那辆车  - 对不起  你等一下
- I love that car. - Excuse me, darling, for just a second.
- 我刚结婚耶  - 你是不是疯了
- I just got married. - Are you nuts?
- 你这么激动干什么  - 你是笨猪呀
- What are you getting excited for? - Are you stupid?
外面有成千上万警察在注意我们
We got a million bulls out there. Everybody's watching us.
你居然弄了辆新车  还说我激动
And you get a fucking car. I'm excited?
那是我用我妈名字登记的  那是结婚礼物嘛
It's under my mother's name. It's a wedding gift.
我不管是登记谁的名字  你是真笨还是假笨呀
I don't give a fuck. Are you stupid?
你没听见我说的吗  什么都不要买
Didn't you hear what I said? Don't buy anything.
特别是大东西  你没听见我这么说的吗
Don't get anything. Nothing big. What's the matter with you?
你到底是怎么搞的
What are you getting excited for?
因为你会连累我们被捕  你白痴啊
Because you're going to get us all fucking pinched. What are you, stupid?
- 你是怎么搞的  - 对不起
- What's the matter with you? - I apologize.
- 我道歉  - 你是怎么搞的
- I'm sorry. - What the fuck is the matter with you?
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起  吉米  在我妈名下
I'm sorry, Jimmy. It's under my mother's name.
说什么  你在跟我争辩吗
What'd you say? You being a fucking wise guy with me?
- 我错了  我道歉  - 我是怎么告诉你的
- I'm sorry. I apologize. - What did I tell you?
听见没有  什么也不许买
What did I tell you? You don't buy anything, you hear me?
什么也不许买
Don't buy anything!
对不起  吉米
I'm sorry, Jimmy.
那个死胖子  他该挂一个笨蛋的牌子
The fat fuck, he ought to wear a sign.
我真不敢相信有这种事  你是变笨了是不是
I can't believe this. Are you stupid or what?
抱歉
Excuse me.
- 你在做什么  - 脱下来
- What's the matter? - Take it off.
- 你在搞什么名堂  - 脱下来
- Why? What's the matter? - Take it off!
难道我没告诉你不要买名贵的东西  不要引人注意吗
Didn't I tell you not to get anything big and not to attract attention?
两天之内  一个买凯迪拉克  一个买貂皮大衣
In two days, one guy gets a Caddy and one gets a $20,000 mink.
- 退回去  - 我会退回去
- Bring it fucking back. - I'll bring it back.
不管怎样  把东西退回去
I don't care what you do. Bring it where you got it before.
- 把它拿出去  - 好  我听见了  快点走吧
- Get it out of here! - All right. Let's go, honey.
这种酒比性爱还爽
This drink here is better than sex, babe.
我要去找史达克  不要东张西望  否则宰了你
I'm gonna go see Stacks. Don't you look at anybody or I'll fucking kill you.
他醋劲好大  我不能看别人一眼  他会杀了我
He's so jealous. If I even look at anyone else, he'll kill me.
不错喔
That's great.
我告诉他们不要引人注意
Tell them all to relax. Don't attract attention.
我一直在找你们
I've been looking all over for you.
圣诞快乐
How are you? Merry Christmas.
我需要钱
Listen, I need the money.
- 轻松点  摩里  好吗  - 吉米  我需要钱呀
- Morrie, relax, okay? It's Christmas. - Jimmy, I need the money.
我是很轻松  但我需要钱
I'm relaxing. I need the money.
- 该做的都做了  我要钱  - 今晚不行  摩里
- I did what I had to do. I need the money. - Not tonight, Morrie.
你听着  我给你们计划得好好的  他欠我那份
Listen, I did my caper. He owes me.
大家都在炫耀新东西
Everybody's flashing their stuff.
显然他们都拿到钱了  我还在穿旧衣裳
Evidently, they got their money. I'm wearing the same shit.
- 今晚不行  - 他们都穿在身上  我一定要跟他谈
- Just not tonight. - They're wearing it. I gotta talk to him.
他应该给我50万
I got $500,000 coming to me.
他一辈子也没弄到过这么多钱
The biggest fucking bundle he ever made in his life.
摩里  我会跟他说  你去喝杯酒
Morrie, I'll go talk to him. Go have a drink, all right?
- 我去找他谈  - 我看这是恶毒
- I'll talk to him. - It's poison in my eyes.
- 摩里宝贝  你没事吧  - 我没事
- Morris, baby, are you all right? - No, I'm not.
吉米
Jimmy
圣诞快乐  你的一份  先尝尝味道
Christmas. Your share. Just a little taste.
我们做到了
We did it!
- 吉米  - 是
- Jimmy. - Yeah.
- 谁呀  - 是我
- Yeah, who is it? - It's me.
彼特  等一下
Pete? One second.
不要学法兰基和强尼  不要暴露
Don't do what Frankie and Johnny did. Don't be a moron with the money.
- 明白吗  - 当然
- Do what's right, you understand? - Yeah.
凯伦  茱迪  露丝  过来!
Karen, Judy, Ruth, come here!
我买了棵最贵的圣诞树
I got the most expensive tree they had.
- 妈咪  你说哪一件好看  - 我每件都喜欢
- What do you think, Mommy? - I love them all.
我喜欢金色那件
I love the gold outfit.
- 圣诞快乐  - 谢谢你
- Merry Christmas. - Thank you.
- 嗯  - 圣诞快乐
- What? - Merry Christmas.
还有
And?
快乐漠路卡节
Happy Hanukkah.
- 好笑喔  - 买你喜欢的东西
- Very funny. - Go get yourself something nice, okay?
德航劫案价值六百万  使我们一生不愁吃穿
Lufthansa should have been our ultimate score. The heist of a lifetime.
每个人都得到一份可观的数目  这样其实就应该足够了
$6 million in cash. More than enough to go around.
史达克  开门呀
Yo, Stacks!
你在干什么呀
Open up! What's up? What're you doing?
你怎么搞的  这家伙还没准备好
What's with you? He ain't ready. I knew you wouldn't be ready.
- 你没带咖啡来吗  - 我又不是送外卖的
- You didn't bring any coffee? - What do I look like, a fucking caterer?
法兰基  煮点咖啡吧  起来呀
Frankie will make coffee. Go ahead, Frankie, make coffee.
我以为你会有个女人在
Thought you had one of your bitches in here.
是有一个  到哪去了
Yeah, I did. Where the fuck is she?
总是少不了黄色书刊和女人
Always got these hot books around, or a bitch, or something.
几点了
What time is it?
- 11点半了  我们应该9点到的  - 马上就好
- It's 11:30. We had to be there by 9:00. - I'll be ready in a minute.
你老是迟到  连你自己的葬礼也会迟到
You're always fucking late. You'd be late for your own fucking funeral.
有什么好看的  把咖啡带走吧
What the fuck you looking at? Make that coffee to go. Let's go.
我是开玩笑啦  操
What the fuck you doing? It's a joke.
你还真要把咖啡带走  放下来啦
Put the fucking pot down. You gonna take the coffee?
史达克总是疯疯癫癫的
Stacks was always crazy.
他没有照计划把卡车处理掉  反而吸大麻吸嗨了
Instead of getting rid of the truck as he was supposed to, he got stoned...
跑去女朋友家  当他醒来  警察已经找到了卡车
went to his girlfriend's, and by the time he woke up, the cops had found the truck.
电视上报告说
It was all over the television.
已在车上找到指纹
They even said they came up with prints off the wheel.
不用多久  他们就会找到史达克的
It was just a matter of time before they got to Stacks.
我必须和你谈谈
I gotta talk to you.
- 来一杯吧  - 来呀  来一杯
- Have a drink. - Have a drink. Come on.
来一杯  好不容易聚在一起喝一杯
Have a drink. What you doing? It's an occasion. Have a drink.
我还是得跟你谈谈
I still gotta talk to you.
什么事呀
What?
- 史达克出了什么事  - 不要担心
- What happened with Stacks? - Don't worry about that.
- 到处都是FBI的人  - 那又怎样  他们能找到什么
- There's feds all over the place. - So what? Where are they gonna go?
- 报上登出来了  - 他很担心
- It's in the papers. - He's worried.
你在担心什么
What are you worried about?
只是电视上  报上都有消息
The television and the newspapers. All the shit's out there.
- 你到底担心什么  - 你太多虑了
- What are you worried about? - You worry too much.
一切美好  什么都不用担心
Everything is beautiful. There's nothing to worry about.
- 你告诉他了没有  - 没有  我还没告诉他
- Didn't you tell him? - I didn't tell him yet.
- 什么事呀  - 猜猜看
- What? - Guess what?
他们要正式让汤米成为黑手党一员
They're gonna make him.
保利要引荐你吗
Paulie's going to make you?
汤米
Tommy.
他们把名单打开了  保利得到批准把他正式加入名单
They opened up the books. Paulie got the okay.
你相信吗  这个意大利杂种
You believe that? This little guinea bastard.
他要上正式名单了  这家伙要成我们的上司了
He's gonna get made. We're gonna work for this guy one day. He's gonna be a boss.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
我真为你高兴  太好了  恭喜你
I'm really happy for you. Great. Congratulations.
我们现在占上风了
Motherfuckers, we got them now.
吉米  我到处在找你  我能跟你说几句话吗
Jimmy, I've been looking all over for you. Can I talk to you a second?
我做的计划  结果我什么也没得到
I mastermind the goddamn thing, I'm left with dick.
要不是我  他们就很辛苦  我要我的钱
They'd be up a creek if not for me. Fuck him! I want my money.
我受够了  我要我的钱
I want my money! I've had it up to here!
那个专门劫香烟的下流鬼
That cheap cigarette hijacker.
- 去他的  我要我的钱  - 去呀  去跟他讲呀
- Fuck him! I want my money! - Good. Go tell him.
你是不是还要嚷嚷
You're gonna keep your mouth shut, or what?
你会拿到钱的
Morrie, you're gonna get your money.
但你不能老是这样烦人家
You just got to stop busting balls.
好  看着我  听见了吗  看着我
All right? Look at me. You hear me? Look at me, okay?
一切不会有问题的
Everything's going to be fine.
亨利
Henry.
好小子  半爱尔兰  半意大利人是吗  我拿意大利腔来唱
Sweetheart, half mick, half guinea? I'll sing with an Italian accent.
我头一次看到吉米那么紧张
I could see for the first time that Jimmy was a nervous wreck.
他同时朝八个方向去想
His mind was going in eight different directions at once.
你想摩里有没有把什么事都告诉他太太
Think Morrie tells his wife everything?
摩里啊
Morrie? Him?
那时候我就知道吉米要把摩里干掉
That's when I knew Jimmy was going to whack Morrie.
事情就是这样  一个人在几分钟之内就被决定了要被干掉
That's how it happens. That's how fast it takes for a guy to get whacked.
你知道他就是那种大嘴巴
He's a nut job. He talks to everybody.
你看过他的电视广告  像只猪
Acts like a jerk in his commercials. Nobody listens to what he says.
谁拿他的话当一回事  他整天说个不停
Nobody fucking cares what he says, he talks so much.
今天晚上把他带来
Make sure you bring him here tonight.
- 知道吗  - 知道
- Okay? - All right.
就这样开始  抱歉  我有没有弄到你眼睛
Start like this. Sorry. Did I get you in the eye?
少惹我了好不好
Stop breaking my balls, all right?
我只是在拖时间
I was just stalling for time.
希望在9点以前能说服吉米
I knew I still had till 8:00 or 9:00 to talk Jimmy out of killing Morrie.
到现在为止  吉米还是认为我同意把摩里干掉
But meanwhile, as far as Jimmy knew, I was going along with the program.
我把他头发拔出来了  我咬了他  他昏迷了
I pulled his hair out of his fucking head. I bit him. He's out cold.
我气死了  我要杀了他
I'm enraged. I wanted to kill this little fuck.
所以我先走开了  我们正要进去
I walk away. We start to go in the fucking joint.
我不想转身  吉米对我这样
I don't want to turn around. Jimmy's going like this to me.
我不想转身
I don't want to fucking turn around.
我不想转身  他妈的  他抬头说
I don't want to turn around. He picks up his fucking head, he says...
我说  不要讲
I said, "Don't say it."
败类
"Jerkoff!"
还能怎样  我就向他扑过去
What are you going to do? What? I fucking fly at him.
我抓住他  开始捶他头  脸
I got him and I'm banging his head, banging his fucking face.
拔他头发
I'm pulling his hair out of his head.
我把他打得稀巴烂
I beat him to a pulp. To a pulp I beat him.
他躺着  浑身是血  我在喘气
He's laying there full of fucking blood. I'm out of breath.
今晚就算了  今晚算了
Forget about tonight. Forget about it.
我心里的负担减轻了
It was a load off my mind.
那个家伙
Poor bastard.
还不知道自己有多危险
He never knew how close he'd come to getting killed.
就算我告诉他  他差点没命  恐怕他也不会相信的
Even if I told him, he would have never believed me.
- 吉米  现在我能跟你谈谈吗  - 你这狗娘养的  你真够烦人
- Jimmy, could I talk to you now? - You're a pisser. A real pisser.
你要现在谈吗  好吧  我们来做个了断
Want to talk now? Okay, let's talk. Let's get it over with.
从来没见过像你这么难缠的人
I've never met a ball buster like you, my whole life.
谁比我还爱你
Who loves you more than I do?
- 我会为你做任何事  - 除了不肯少来烦我
- I'd do anything for you. - Except to stop busting my balls.
- 我们去喝咖啡吧  - 去餐厅还是别的地方
- Let's go have coffee. - Want to go to the diner?
我们去大道上的餐厅
We'll go to the diner on the boulevard.
- 哪一间呢  - 洛克威大道  24小时营业
- Which diner? - Rockaway Boulevard. It's open 24 hours.
- 有没有丹麦蛋糕  - 他们什么都有
- They got Danishes? - They got everything.
我要带几个回去给贝儿
Let's pick up some Danishes for Belle.
你有没有听到我们在波士顿安排篮球赛放水的事
Hear about the points we were shaving up in Boston?
那真是太棒了
It's terrific. Nunzio...
我以为他永远也不会闭嘴
I thought he'd never shut up.
没人比他更令人讨厌
What a pain in the ass.
- 你要怎么处理他  - 把他分尸  丢掉  把车也丢掉
- What'll we do with him? - Chop him up and get rid of the car.
然后打电话给我
Call me when you're through.
- 法兰基  我们来把他大卸八块吧  - 好吧
- Frank, let's chop him up. - All right.
你要去哪里  你昏头啦
Where you going, you dizzy motherfucker, you?
你不是说要把他解了吗
You said chop him up.
不是在这里  去查理那儿  在这里怎么切
At Charlie's, not here! Where are you gonna chop him here?
你在做什么  快离开这里
Come on, what are you doing? Get out of here.
还不如让他开车
I got a better shot letting him drive.
车引擎是冷的
The car's cold.
热什么鬼车  快离开现场
Get the fuck out of here! What, warm it up? Get out of here!
- 是谁  - 是贝尔  开门
- Who is it? - It's Belle. Open up.
是贝尔  让我进来
It's Belle. Let me in.
摩里没有回家  他失踪了  我知道他一定出事了
Morris didn't come home. He's missing. I know something's happened.
冷静一点
Calm down.
他失踪了  我知道出事了
He's missing! I know something happened.
他大概是喝醉了  倒在那里睡着了
He's probably drunk and fell asleep somewhere.
27年了  他从来没有在外过夜  而不打电话给我的
In 27 years, he's never been away all night without calling.
肯定出事了  你们一定晓得
I know something's happened. I know you know.
我上楼去换衣服  先送你回家  然后去找他
Let me get changed. I'll take you home, then look for him.
- 我是从家里来的  我一直打电话  - 他在玩牌吧
- I've been home! I've been on the phone... - He's playing cards.
- 你要我怎么跟贝尔讲  - 谁他妈在乎
- What'll I tell Belle? - Who gives a fuck?
就说他跟野女人私奔了  关你什么事
Tell her he ran off with some broad. What do you care?
- 你看  - 不要跟他们作对
- Watch this. - Don't fuck with them.
就算坐一点牢  也总算捣了他们的蛋
I do it all the time. I'll bust their balls.
别给他们这个机会来得意了
Don't give them the satisfaction, the fucks.
走吧  我们去兜风
Come on, fuckos. Let's go for a ride.
他们一夜没睡了
Keep them up all night.
待会儿见
I'll see you later.
吉米想把每一个能把他和劫案牵连在一起的人都除掉
Jimmy was cutting every link between himself and the robbery...
好在跟我一点关系都没有
but it had nothing to do with me.
我给吉米一些可劫对象的消息  他则给我钱
I gave Jimmy the tip and he gave me some Christmas money.
之后我没再提大劫案的事
From then on, I kept my mouth shut.
我知道钱在吉米那里
I knew Jimmy. He had the cash. It was his.
他只拿一点钱孝敬保利而已
He kicked some money upstairs to Paulie, but that was it.
要他把钱分给有功劳的人  那是不可能的事
It made him sick to turn the money over to the guys who stole it.
他宁愿把他们杀了  反正关我什么事
He'd rather whack them. Anyway, what did I care?
我也不想向吉米要求什么
I wasn't asking for anything.
吉米倒从我的匹兹堡路线收获不少
And Jimmy was making nice money through my Pittsburgh connections.
大劫案之后几个月  仍然到处发现死尸
Still, months after the robbery they were finding bodies all over.
当他们在冷冻车库里找到卡本的尸体
When they found Carbone in the meat truck...
他已经冷冻得
he was frozen so stiff...
要花两天才能解冻  才能拿出来解剖
it took them two days to thaw him out for the autopsy.
我从没见过吉米那么高兴
Still, I never saw Jimmy so happy.
他简直像个孩子  匹兹堡给我们带来钱财
He was like a kid. We had money coming in through my Pittsburgh people...
德航劫案的调查也渐渐冷却下来
and even after a while, the Lufthansa thing began to calm down.
那天早上令吉米高兴的原因
What made Jimmy so happy that morning...
是因为汤米要被引荐
was that this was the day that Tommy was being made.
他兴奋得好像他自己要被引荐似的
Jimmy was so excited, you'd think he was being made.
他至少打了四次电话到汤米家
He must have made four calls to Tommy's house.
引荐礼完成之后以信号表示
They had a signal set up, so he'd know the minute the ceremony was over.
- 妈  你在哪儿  - 在这里呀
- Ma, where are you? - Here I am.
- 你回来啦  - 回来  我正要出去呀
- You're home. - Home? I'm leaving.
- 不错吧  - 你看起来帅极了
- You look lovely. - I look good, huh?
千万小心  恭喜你了  祝你好运
You look wonderful. Be careful. Congratulations.
我爱你  别再画宗教画了  拜托你
I love you. Don't paint any more religious pictures, please.
- 上帝与你同在  - 再见  妈妈
- God be with you. - Bye, Ma.
我们都以好兄弟互相称呼
We always called each other goodfellas.
你对某人说
You'd say to somebody:
你会喜欢他  他是好兄弟  是我们一伙的
"You'll like this guy. He's all right. He's a goodfella, one of us."
你明白吗
You understand?
我们都是好兄弟
We were goodfellas. Wiseguys.
吉米和我都因为有爱尔兰血统  而不能被引荐
But Jimmy and I could never be made because we had Irish blood.
即便我母亲是西西里人也没有用
It didn't matter my mother was Sicilian.
你一定要百分之百意大利血统才能被正式引荐
To become a member of a crew, you've got to be 100% Italian...
他们要能追踪出你所有亲戚的来历
so they can trace your relatives back to the old country.
那是最高的荣誉
It's the highest honor they can give you.
象征你已属于一个家庭  一个团体
It means you belong to a family and a crew.
那意谓着再没有人敢伤害你
It means nobody can fuck around with you.
你却可以任意欺侮
It also means you could fuck around with anybody...
那些不属于任何家族的人
just as long as they aren't also a member.
好像拥有偷劫的执照  做任何事的执照
It's like a license to steal. A license to do anything.
你被正式引荐有多少年了
How many years ago since you were made?
- 我是老人了  30年前  - 30年前呀
- I'm an old-timer. 30 years ago. - Thirty years?
是呀  有很多值得回忆的事呀
Brings back a lot of memories.
派克山当时也只不过一粒青春痘嘛
Pike's Peak was a pimple then, wasn't it?
对吉米来说  汤米被引荐
As far as Jimmy was concerned, with Tommy being made...
就像我们都被引荐了一样
it was like we were all being made.
我们之中有人当了会员了
We would now have one of our own as a member.
- 是谁  - 是韦力
- Who's this? - This is Vinnie.
怎么回事  仪式完成了吗
Vinnie. What happened? Did we get straightened out?
发生一点问题  我们尽力了
No, we had a problem. We tried to do everything we could.
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
我是说他死了  我们也无能为力
You know what I mean. He's gone, and we couldn't do nothing about it.
- 就这样  - 你是什么意思
- That's it. - What do you mean?
他死了
He's gone.
就这样
That's it.
我早就知道会这样  狗娘养的  我不能相信
I knew it! I can't fucking believe it.
发生什么事啦
What happened?
- 他们干掉他了  - 操
- They fucking whacked him - Fuck.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
那是替比利·贝兹报仇
It was revenge for Billy Batts...
还有一些旧的积怨
and a lot of other things.
就是这样
And that's that.
我们是一点办法也没有
There was nothing we could do about it.
贝兹是黑手党的  汤米还不是
Batts was a made man and Tommy wasn't.
我们只是老老实实的逆来顺受
We had to sit still and take it.
意大利人圈子就是这样  一种毫无道理的规定
It was among the Italians. It was real greaseball shit.
他们甚至打在汤米脸上
They even shot Tommy in the face...
让他妈妈不能给他开棺瞻仰
so his mother couldn't give him an open coffin at the funeral.
1980年5月11日  星期日  上午6点55分
我本来预备好要忙一整天的
I was gonna be busy all day. I had to drop off some guns at Jimmy's...
我要拿枪去给吉米配消音器
to match some silencers he had.
去医院接我弟弟  带他回家吃晚饭
I had to pick up my brother at the hospital and drive him home.
然后去取匹兹堡来的货
I had to pick up some new Pittsburgh stuff for Lois...
交给露易丝  让她将货空运给亚特兰大附近的客人
to fly down to some customers I had near Atlanta.
我马上就知道他不会要那些枪  我知道我的钱泡汤了
Right away, I knew he didn't want them, and I'd be stuck for the money.
因为他要我才买的  现在他又不要了
I only bought them because he wanted them, and now he didn't.
这些有什么鬼用  一个都配不上  你在搞什么
What good are these? None of them fit. What's the matter with you?
我才不付钱呢
I'm not paying for it.
我一句话也没讲  吉米气得连再见都没说
I didn't say a thing. Jimmy was so pissed off, he didn't even say goodbye.
别再吸毒了  你的脑子都快不管用了
Stop the drugs. They're making your mind into mush!
- 听见没有  - 我把它们带回去就是了
- You hear me? - I'll take them back.
上午8点05分
那些匹兹堡家伙  总是在买枪
My Pittsburgh guys always wanted guns.
我下午反正要去见他们  去取货
Since I would see them in the afternoon to pick up a delivery...
我蛮肯定我能赚回本的
I was pretty sure I'd get my money back.
我的老天呀
Oh, my God.
上午8点45分
当我终于到了医院接麦可  医生说我该住院了
When I finally got to the hospital, Michael's doctor wanted to put me in bed.
上帝呀  你发生什么事了
Jesus Christ, what happened to you?
刚才差点撞车
I almost got into an accident on the way here.
我描述了车祸  又说昨夜狂欢没睡
And I told him I was partying all night.
- 我没事  - 好啦  到这边来
- I'm fine. - Come on. Get over here.
- 医师  我没事  - 我给你做个检查
- Doc, I'm fine. - Let me check you out.
好啦
Come on.
他很同情我  只给了我10毫克镇静剂
He took mercy on me, gave me 10 milligrams of Valium...
就让我回去了
and sent me home.
我计划把弟弟送回家  同时把凯伦接上
My plan was to drop off my brother at the house and pick up Karen.
你看见没有  一架直升机
There it is. You see that helicopter right there?
就在我们前面  它跟了我一早上了
Right in front of us, there. I think it's been following me all morning.
- 别瞎扯了  它跟踪你干什么  - 我告诉你
- Get the fuck out. What are you, nuts? - I'm telling you.
我也不知道是怎么回事
I don't know what's going on.
这是我第三次看到它  我去医院接你也看到了
It's the third time I've seen it. At the hospital I saw it.
中途停了两次  每次都看到它
I had to make some stops. I've seen it every time.
我跑了好多地方  整天都看到它
I've been all over town and I've seen it all day.
那天由我做晚餐
I was cooking dinner that night.
上午11点30分
我必须把肉汁熬出来做蕃茄配料
I had to start braising the beef and veal shanks for the tomato sauce.
是麦可最喜欢的菜  我做了肉酱
It was Michael's favorite. I was making ziti with meat gravy...
还打算烤辣椒
and I'm planning to roast some peppers over the flames...
橄榄油豆  大蒜等
put on some string beans with olive oil. I had some beautiful cutlets...
我还有切得很好的小牛肉
that were cut just right...
打算炸好了当开胃菜
that I was going to fry up as an appetizer.
我在家停留了约一小时
So, I was home for about an hour.
现在我计划提早吃晚饭
My plan was to start the dinner early...
凯伦和我可以把枪推销掉
so Karen and I could unload the guns Jimmy didn't want...
同时把货取回来给露易丝
then get the package for Lois...
由她跑一趟亚特兰大
to take to Atlanta for her trip later that night.
我不时从窗户看出去  直升机已经不在了
I kept looking out the window, and I saw that the helicopter was gone.
麦可  注意蕃茄汁好吗  你留在这里陪麦可叔叔
Michael, keep an eye on the sauce. Stay here with your Uncle Michael.
我请麦可注意配料  我和凯伦就出去了
So I asked my brother to watch the sauce, and Karen and I started out.
天呀  我看见了
Oh, God. I see it.
- 我看见了  就在那儿  - 该死
- I see it. Look, it's right there. - Damn!
- 就是它  - 就在那边
- That's it. - There it is.
我们去你妈妈家
We got to get to your mother's.
看见了吧  我告诉你了嘛
See, I told you.
是很奇怪
It's funny.
- 但并不是世界末日  - 我们先去你妈妈家
- It's not the end of the world. - We're going to your mother's.
进去告诉你妈妈  外面的东西不要碰  好吗
Go inside, tell your mother not to touch anything outside the house. Nothing.
为什么不到你妈妈家去  非要到我妈家来
We couldn't go to your mother's house? You had to come here.
来  去购物吧
Let's go shopping.
没有  我没疯  这死东西跟了我一早上
I'm not nuts, it's been following me all morning.
中午12点30分
我跟你讲啦
I'm telling you.
好啦  好啦  他说我疑心病太重
Fine. Fine. He thinks I'm paranoid!
我应该把直升机带到他那  看我是不是疑心病
I should bring him the helicopter, then we'll see how paranoid I am.
我们进去吧
Come on, let's go inside.
下午1点30分
不见了
Yeah, it's gone.
-我听不见声音了  -来吧  回你妈妈家
- I don't hear anything. - Let's go back to your mother's.
下午3点30分
- 还可以吗  - 太好了  太好了
- They all right? - Beautiful. They're great.
我不是说了  你是疑心病吗  我告诉你  他是多心罢了
Didn't I tell you, you were paranoid? Didn't I tell him?
是呀  我需要吸一口
Yeah. I need a hit.
你要看直升机吗  来  我给你看直升机
Want to see helicopters? Come on, I'll show you helicopters.
我今天看够直升机了
I've seen enough helicopters for one day, thank you.
我计划先回家  把包裹准备给露易丝带上路
I had to get home and get the package ready for Lois to take on her trip.
我还要去珊蒂家  让她把奎宁注射进去
Also, I had to get to Sandy's to give the package a whack with quinine.
加上珊蒂一定会啰嗦我没去陪她
Plus, I knew Sandy would get on my ass.
我还得做菜  还有帮助露易丝启程
I had the cooking to finish, and I had to get Lois ready for her trip.
- 是珊蒂啦  这是怎样啊  - 她烦得很啦
- It's Sandy. What is this? - She's a pain in the ass.
- 你什么时候过来  - 我一小时之内会去
- When are you coming over? - In an hour.
- 你今天在我这儿过夜吧  - 不行  我要照顾我弟弟
- You staying tonight, right? - I can't. I got my brother tonight.
好了  别说了  再见
Come on, stop. We'll talk about it later, okay? Goodbye.
- 哈罗  - 你准备好了没有
- Hello? - It's me. You ready?
叫麦可注意不要让配料太浓  要不停搅拌
Tell Michael not to let the sauce stick. Keep stirring it.
- 亨利说不要让配料太浓  - 我在搅拌
- Henry says don't let the sauce stick. - I'm stirring it.
- 你知道该怎么做吗  - 知道  知道
- Listen, you know what to do? - Yeah, yeah.
不要跟我来  知道  知道  这一套  这是很重要的事
Don't "yeah, yeah" me, Lois. This is important.
你到外面去再打电话
Make sure you leave the house when you make the call.
懂不懂  用公用电话  你听见没有  不是闹着玩的
Understand me? Call from an outside line. I mean it.
上帝  你把我当呆子呀  少烦我  我知道该怎么做
Jesus, you must think I'm dumb. Why are you bugging me? I know what to do.
没常识  你最好别弄糟事情
You little hick, just make sure you do it.
你就是会让人不舒服
You can be such a pain.
- 你就照我的意思做  - 知道啦
- Hey! Just do it! - Okay.
真没法相信  我生命中的每个女人都是这样的
Un-fucking-believable. All of them. Every fucking girl in my life.
- 他说什么  - 没什么
- What did he say? - Nothing.
她挂上电话以后  你猜她做了什么
What does she do after she hangs up with me?
虽然她说了一大堆  知道  知道  虽然我一再警告她
After everything I told her? After all her "yeah, yeah"bullshit?
她居然拿起电话就打
She picks up the phone and calls from the house.
假如被装了窃听器  那对方什么都清楚了
If anybody was listening, they'd know everything.
一袋包裹将从我家送出
They'd know a package was leaving my house...
甚至班机号码及时间
and they'd even have the time and flight number, thanks to her.
傍晚6点30分
我一到家就开始做晚餐
As soon as I got home, I started cooking.
离露易丝起飞时间有几小时
I had a few hours until Lois' flight.
我告诉弟弟注意炉子
I told my brother to watch the stove.
可怜的小子  一整天都在看蕃茄汁和直升机
All day long the guy's been watching helicopters and tomato sauce.
我得去珊蒂家把货混好再回来做肉汁
I had to drive over to Sandy's, mix the stuff, then get back to the gravy.
晚上8点30分
你以为可以随便来  下了床  屁股一拍就走人吗
Do you think you can come over here, fuck me, and leave?
- 别这样嘛  - 你还有更好的地方要去吗
- Come on. - You got someplace better to go?
别这样讲
Don't talk like that. Come on.
- 你没事吧  - 没事啦
- You all right? - Yeah, sure.
你相信我吗
You believe me?
Do you believe me?
你相信我吗
- 那是最后一批了吧  - 是呀
- That the last one? - Yeah.
你这狗娘养的骗子  我恨你
You lying son of a bitch. I hate you!
晚上10点45分
不要在桌子上喂狗
Please stop feeding the dog from the table...
更不要用盘子喂他  不许这样
from the plate on top of it. Stop it.
- 我不喂不行  - 没什么不行的
- I have to. - You don't have to.
我得回家一趟
I got to go home.
什么叫你得回家一趟
What do you mean, you got to go home?
我带着这些货跑了一早上
I've been carrying this all day.
你该开始把它粘在大腿上  我们差不多该走了
We got to start taping it to your leg. We got to go soon.
我要回去拿我的帽子
I got to go home and get my hat.
你在开我玩笑呀  什么鬼帽子
Forget your fucking hat. Are you kidding me?
要我载你回去拿帽子
So I need a trip to Rockaway because you want your hat?
我需要它  那是我的幸运帽  没有它我绝不上路
I need it, I got to have it. It's my lucky hat. I never fly without it.
露易丝  你知道我们所做的事有多严重吗
Lois, do you understand what we are involved in here?
我管不了那么多  没有帽子  我就不上飞机
I don't care. I need my hat. I won't fly without it.
我能怎么办  她坚持要她的帽子
What could I do if she insisted I drive her home for her goddamn hat?
我把包裹藏在厨房  我只好带她回去
I hid the package in the kitchen and went to take her home.
帽子
A hat?
这是什么情况
What the fuck is this?
警察  别动  不许动  你这人渣
Police! Freeze! Don't you move, you motherfucker...
否则我会把你脑浆打出来  慢慢熄火
or I'll blow your brains out. Shut the car off slowly.
刹那之间  我以为我已经死了
For a second, I thought I was dead.
但当我听到吵杂声  我知道那些是警察
But when I heard all the noise, I knew they were cops.
只有条子  才用那种口气说话
Only cops talk that way.
你他妈老实点
Don't fucking move.
如果是帮派兄弟  我会连一点声音都听不见
If they had been wiseguys, I wouldn't have heard a thing.
就被打死了
I would have been dead.
麦可  把门锁上
Michael, lock the door!
余波
你最后一次被捕是什么时候
Talk to me. When was the last time you took a collar?
说呀
Fuckhead, I'm talking to you.
你一个字也不肯说  你什么也不用说  我不在乎
You don't want to say a fucking word, don't. I don't really give a fuck.
等你要被关25年的时候  看你还能对你朋友多忠心
You'll do 25 years. See how much of a good guy you'll be then.
我一直以为直升机上的人
All day I thought the guys in the helicopter...
是为了德航劫案在跟踪我  原来他们是缉毒组的
were local cops busting my balls over Lufthansa. They turned out to be narcs.
把律师叫来就好了
Just get the lawyer.
他们盯了我一个月了  窃听电话  跟踪行程  全套都来
They'd been on me a month. Phone taps, surveillance, everything.
你认识这些伙计  你的搭档都被抓了
You know the boys. All the pals are here.
你要是不说  我会整晚像苍蝇一样叮咬你
You don't want to talk to me, you'll have a problem all night.
在纽约  这任何一项罪名都可以判你25年监禁
Each one of these counts holds 25-to-life in New York State.
25年呀  老兄  你身心都会受不了那种压力的
Twenty-five fucking years, pal. I'll slap your fucking head inside out.
你们去哪儿  买杂货呀
What, were you guys grocery shopping?
要做蛋糕呀  你也要做蛋糕呀
Are we going to make a cake? You going to make a fucking cake?
有没有找到什么好东西呀
You got anything good in there?
是不是白粉呀
Is it good?
再见啦  鸟蛋
Bye-bye, dickhead.
阿迪卡监狱见啦
See you in Attica, dick.
我跟吉米谈过了  他愿意给我一点钱
I spoke to Jimmy. He offered to give me some money.
他想知道发生什么事了  他要跟你谈谈
He just wants to know what's happening. He just wants to talk to you.
去他的吉米  去他的钱
Fuck Jimmy and his money.
我一定得想办法出去  把事情向保利摆平  否则我死定了
I got to straighten out everything with Paulie or I'm dead.
那也许你在里面还安全点
Then you're better off staying in here.
他们在里面一样可以干掉我  也许还更容易
They could whack me in here as easy as outside, maybe even easier.
他们都担心我会把事情抖出来
They're afraid I'll rat them out.
他们已经在避我了  我在里面迟早是死路一条
People are already walking away from me. I'm dead in here.
你一定要把我弄出去
You got to get me out.
凯伦终于让她妈妈拿房子抵押  保我出来
Karen finally got her mother to put her house up for my bail and I was out.
我有种感觉  我一出监牢就会被杀
I remember I had this feeling I would be killed right outside the jail.
我知道保利还在生我的气  他那种死脾气的人
I knew Paulie was still pissed at me, and he's such a hothead.
我也替吉米担心
And I was worried about Jimmy.
吉米自己也很清楚状况  如果保利知道他跟我在搞贩毒
See, Jimmy knew if Paulie found out he was into drug deals with me...
他会比我还先死
Paulie would have Jimmy whacked even before me.
情势对我很不利
This is the bad time.
到家之后我才有点安全感
I didn't feel safe until I got home.
现在我要好好计划保住性命  尽快把货脱手
Now my plan was to stay alive long enough to sell off the dope...
躲起来一阵子  让我慢慢把所有事情摆平
the cops never found, then disappear until I can get things straightened out.
操
Fuck!
- 凯伦  我藏起来的那批货呢  - 我冲下马桶了
- Where's the stuff I left, Karen? - I flushed it down the toilet.
你干了什么
You what?
我该怎么办  到处都是条子
What was I supposed to do? They were all over the house.
那是我们的全部财产  价值6万块  我需要那些钱
That was worth $60,000! I need that money! That's all we got!
我能怎么办  他们有搜查令
What was I supposed to do? They had a search warrant!
你为什么要这么做  我们只有那些钱
That's all the money we had! I was depending on that! Why did you do that?
我没办法  他们一定会找到的
I had to. They were going to find it!
- 他们绝不会找到的  - 我敢发誓
- They would have never found it! - They would have, I swear to you!
他们一定会找到的
They would've found it!
你为什么要这样做
Why did you do that?
- 他们一定会找到的  - 你为什么要这样做
- They would have found it. - Why did you do that, Karen?
我的天呀
Oh, my God!
- 我是迫不得已  - 我的天呀
- I had to do it. - Oh, my God.
保利  我真的很抱歉
Paulie, I'm really sorry.
我不知道该说什么才好  我知道我犯了严重的错误
I don't know what else to say. I know I fucked up.
你搞砸了
Yeah, you fucked up.
但我现在没事了
But I'm all right now.
你可以相信我  我拿我孩子做保证
I can be trusted now. I'm clean. On my kids, I'm clean.
你睁着眼对我说谎
You looked in my eyes and lied to me.
把我当冤大头
You treated me like a fucking jerk.
毫无分量
Like I was never nothing to you.
你警告过我们  所以我更不敢向你说实话了
After what you said, I couldn't come to you.
我从那时起到现在
You know, I was ashamed.
都很惭愧
I'm ashamed now.
但是我已经走投无路了  保利
But I got nowhere else to go, Paulie.
我现在只有求你了  我真的需要你的帮助
You're all I've got. And I really need your help. I really do.
拿着
Take this.
从现在起我不认识你了
And now I've got to turn my back on you.
三千两百块
$3,200.
一生替他做事  他就给了我三千两百块
That's what he gave me. $3,200 for a lifetime.
连买棺材都不够
It wasn't even enough to pay for the coffin.
- 我们得跑路了  - 我不想跑
- We got to get out. - I don't want to run.
难道你要我放弃一切  找地方躲起来吗
I don't want to. Am I supposed to pick up and leave everything? Go hiding?
我不要  那就是你所要的生活吗
I don't want to do that. Is that what you want?
我们留在这里  我们就死定了
If we stay around here, we're dead.
死定了  懂不懂
You got it? We're dead.
他们说得没错
They're right.
你药嗑太多了  你已经完全神经过敏了
You took too much of that stuff. You're totally paranoid.
他还好吧  有没有找他麻烦
How's he doing? Busting his balls or what?
他还好
He's okay.
他把嗑药的毛病改掉了
They sobered him up.
那就好
Good. Very good. Glad to hear it.
他有没有告诉你  条子问了他一些什么样的问题
You know what kind of questions they're asking him?
吉米  我不知道
Jimmy, I don't know.
我心情太乱了  我又没有钱
I got my mind on so many other things. I got no money...
孩子们都已经会看报纸了
The girls are old enough to read the newspapers.
你回去叫他马上给我打电话
Tell him he's got to call me. Okay?
我们要好好处理这件事  这是非常重要的
As soon as you talk to him, he's got to call me. It's important.
他不知道我来找你  他现在不是很正常
He doesn't know I came here to see you. It's like he's crazy.
- 先拿去救急  有几千块钱  - 谢了  吉米
- Take this. It's a couple of thousands. - Thanks, Jimmy.
不要太担心好吗  一切都会过去的
Don't worry, everything will be all right.
我有一批很漂亮的迪奥女裙
I got some beautiful Dior dresses. You want to have them?
去挑几件喜欢的吧
Pick out a few for yourself.
- 挑给我妈妈  - 可以  没问题  随便挑
- For my mom. - Yeah, whatever.
不  不  是在转角仓库
No. It's over here. In the store on the corner.
因为是赃物  我放在角落
It's swag, so I got it down on the corner.
去吧  甜心  再见
Go ahead, sweetheart, I'll see you.
- 谢谢  吉米  - 不用担心
- Thanks, Jimmy. - Don't worry.
- 我知道  - 不要忘了  打电话给我
- I'll try. - Don't forget, he's got to call me.
- 这边吗  - 一直走
- Over here? - Right down there.
一直走  在转角
It's over there, on the corner.
就在那里
Right there.
不是  去呀  就在里面
No, go ahead. It's right in there.
不用了  吉米  我在赶时间
No, Jimmy. I'm in a hurry!
我妈在看孩子  我得回去
My mom's watching the kids! I got to get home!
以后再来拿
I'll come back later!
凯伦
Karen!
发生什么事了
What happened?
没事
Nothing.
- 到底什么事  - 我只是突然怕起来了
- What happened? - I just got scared.
车钥匙拿了没有
Got the keys?
- 到底什么事  - 我只是害怕起来了
- What happened, Karen? - I just got scared. It's okay.
- 没事吧  - 现在没事了
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
如果你是黑手党员  你永远不会知道几时会被杀
If you're part of a crew, nobody ever tells you they're going to kill you.
没人会事先通知你的
It doesn't happen that way.
也不像电影里先大吵大骂
There aren't any arguments or curses like in the movies.
来杀你的人面带笑容  像是你很亲近的朋友
Your murderers come with smiles. They come as your friends.
他们一直很关心你
People who cared for you all your life.
在你有困难时  他们总会来帮助你
They always seem to come when you're weakest and most in need of their help.
所以我跟吉米约好在人多的地方见面
So I met Jimmy in a crowded place we both knew.
我早到了15分钟  可吉米已经比我先到了
I got there 15 minutes early, and Jimmy was already there.
他占了靠窗的雅座  凡是来餐厅的人  他都看得见
He took the booth near the window so he could see everyone who drove up.
他要确认我没有被跟踪
He wanted to make sure I wasn't tailed.
他很紧张  什么也没吃
He was jumpy. He hadn't touched a thing.
表面看来一点也没事
On the surface, everything was supposed to be fine.
我们应该是要商量我的案子
We were supposed to be discussing my case.
但我可以感觉到吉米在试探我是否会为了救自己而出卖他
But I had a feeling Jimmy was trying to sense if I'd rat on him to save my neck.
我一直提醒你  不要在电话上谈事情
I been telling you your whole life, don't talk on the phone.
现在你明白了
Now you understand?
我想你胜诉的机会很大  一切会没问题的
It's going to be okay. You got a good chance to beat the case.
那个小子  你知道我是在说谁吧
You know that kid from the city we were talking about? You know?
那是个告密者  他一被捕就把所有的人都招供出来了
The kid turned out to be a rat. As soon as he got pinched, he ratted on everybody.
我知道他现在躲在哪里
I know where he is. He's hiding now.
懂不懂我说的
Know what I'm saying?
你想你能和安东尼一方面度假  一方面把他解决掉吗
Would you have a problem going with Anthony to take care of that?
没问题
No, not at all.
这样他们就没证人了
That way they got nothing.
吉米从来没有叫我替他除掉任何人
Jimmy had never asked me to whack somebody before.
现在他叫我和安东尼一起到佛罗里达去为他杀人
But now he's asking me to go to Florida and do a hit with Anthony.
那时候我就知道  如果我去了佛州  我不会活着回来
That's when I knew I would never have come back from Florida alive.
不论你要把我们搬去哪里  我说过
Whenever you move me, I asked once and I'll tell you again...
我不去寒冷的地方
I don't want to go any place cold.
你并没有选择余地
You don't have a choice in that matter.
到底是谁管这个
Come on. Whoever fucking controls it...
帮个忙  只要不是寒冷地方就行
just no place cold. Do that for me. I'm trying to...
他有气管炎
He's bronchial, that's why.
如果检查后他真有气管炎  我们会列入考虑因素
If he's legitimately bronchial, we'll consider that.
我希望去不冷的地方
I'd like to go someplace not cold.
我能问一些问题吗  我父母会怎么样
Can I ask you some questions? What about my parents?
他们怎么啦
What about them?
我能不能见他们  跟他们通消息
Am I going to see them? Am I going to talk to them?
怎么跟他们联络
Don't I have some kind of contact with them?
不能
No.
等一等  你是说
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. You mean to tell me that...
就算我父母生病了  我也不能去看他们吗
God forbid something happens to my parents, they get sick, I can't see them?
也许可以特别安排  如果他们病了
Maybe something can be worked out if they're sick...
情形特殊的话
if there's extraordinary circumstances...
我不能这样做  亨利
I can't do this. I can't do this, Henry.
我不能留下我父母不管
I can't leave my parents.
抱歉  凯伦  我跟你说了
Excuse me, Karen, I told you before.
除非你跟孩子们和我在一起  我不会同意这个证人保护行动
I'm not going to do this unless you and the kids come with me.
我没有办法一个人捱过这些
I can't do it without you.
你要怎么做就怎么做  可是  就这样
So, you do whatever, but... that's it.
- 你们需要亨利  并不需要我  对不对  - 没错
- You need Henry, not me, right? - That's right.
老实说  我并不在乎你去不去
Frankly, I don't care whether you go or not.
如果能使他成为一个快乐而有用的证人  我希望你去
If it'll make him a better witness, I'd like you to be with him.
他们要的是亨利  不是我
They want Henry, not me.
亨利会受到保护  他们动不了他
Henry'll be in the protection program. They can't get to him.
他们只能从你跟孩子身上动手来伤害亨利
They can only get to him by getting to you or your kids.
假如他参与这次行动  你的处境就很危险
If he goes into the program, you're in danger...
- 我什么也不知道呀  - 不要给我
- I don't know anything. - Don't give me...
天真无邪那一套
the babe-in-the-woods routine.
我听过那些电话录音  你在电话中大谈白粉
I've listened to those wiretaps, and I've heard you talk about cocaine.
你跟亨利一通电话接着一通
Conversation after conversation you talked to Henry on the phone.
不管他是进监牢
It doesn't matter. Whether he goes to jail...
还是胜诉了  他都一样是没命
or stays on the streets and beats the case, he's a dead man.
你们心里都很清楚
He knows it and you know it.
我们的孩子怎么办  他们要上学呀
What about the kids and school?
总不能把他们留下
Will they get left back? I mean, what goes on?
你们为什么不到华尔街去抓那些真正的坏人
Go to Wall Street and get real crooks.
卖西装给你们的人  真有幽默感
Whoever sold you those suits had a sense of humor.
归根结底  和我们配合才是唯一救你们的方法
What it comes down to is we're your only salvation.
我们会保障你们的生命  也会不让他去坐牢
We'll save your life and his life, and we'll keep you out of jail.
今天早上你曾把你的背景向陪审团说明
This morning you told the jury about your background.
要从人群中消失并不是一件困难的事
It was easy for us to disappear.
房子是岳母的名字
My house was in my mother-in-law's name.
车是我老婆的名字
My cars were registered to my wife.
社会福利卡以及驾照都是假的
My Social Security cards and driver's licenses were phonies.
没投过票  没缴过税
I never voted or paid taxes.
唯一能表示有我这个人存在的是出生证明和犯罪记录
My birth certificate and arrest sheet was all you'd ever have to know I was alive.
- 那个人在法庭内吗  - 是的
- Do you see him here in this courtroom? - Yes.
你能为陪审团将他指证出来吗
Will you please point him out for the jury?
法官大人  请记录下来  希尔先生已正式指证了詹姆斯·康威
Let the record reflect that Mr. Hill identified the defendant, James Conway.
你也认识一位叫保罗·西席罗的人
Do you also know a man named Paul Cicero?
- 那个人在这个法庭内吗  - 是的
- Do you see him in the courtroom? - Yes.
你能为陪审团将他指证出来吗
Can you point him out for the jury?
法官大人  请记录下希尔先生已指证了保罗·西席罗
Let the record reflect that Mr. Hill identified the defendant, Paul Cicero.
法官大人  我这里有一份文件
Your Honor, I have a document...
对我来说  最困难的就是从那种生活方式中走出来
The hardest thing was leaving the life.
我还是喜爱那种生活
I still love the life.
我们像电影明星一样被礼遇
We were treated like movie stars with muscle.
只要开口  要什么有什么
We had it all, just for the asking.
老婆  母亲  孩子  人人都能享受
Our wives, mothers, kids, everybody rode along.
一包纸袋的珠宝藏在厨房
I had paper bags filled with jewelry stashed in the kitchen.
一缸白粉就放在床边
I had a sugar bowl full of coke next to the bed.
称为鼠辈  是因为老鼠为了求生存  什么事都会做
People call them rats because rats do anything to survive. Isn't that right?
- 抗议  - 抗议成立
- Objection! - Objection sustained.
- 至于老鼠我就不知道了  - 你太了解了
- I know nothing about being a rat. - You know everything about it.
只要一通电话  什么都有
Anything I wanted was a phone call away.
免费的汽车  城里所有的黑帮分子玩乐的地方都能自由进出
Free cars. Keys to a dozen hideout flats all over the city.
一个周末可以下注两三万
I'd bet $20,000, $30,000 over a weekend...
也可以一周内把赢的钱全花光  有时候也借高利贷来还赌债
then blow the winnings in a week or go to the sharks to pay the bookies.
不过一点关系都没有
It didn't matter.
钱花光了  我只要出去多抢一点就行了
It didn't mean anything. When I was broke I would go out and rob some more.
我们控制一切
We ran everything.
收买条子  收买律师  甚至收买法官
We paid off cops. We paid off lawyers. We paid off judges.
每个人都受贿  只要我们肯出钱
Everybody had their hands out. Everything was for the taking.
现在都结束了
And now it's all over.
难就难在这里
That's the hardest part.
如今一切都不同了
Today everything is different.
我得像其他人一样等排班
There's no action. I have to wait around like everyone else.
连像样的菜都吃不到
Can't even get decent food.
我搬来以后曾点过意大利面  加意大利蕃茄配料
After I got here I ordered spaghetti with marinara sauce...
结果上的是鸡蛋面加蕃茄酱
and I got egg noodles and ketchup.
我成为了无名小卒淡泊一生
I'm an average nobody.
下半辈子得过得像个可怜虫
I get to live the rest of my life like a schnook.
亨利·希尔目前仍在接受证人保护行动
他于1987年在西雅图以贩毒罪名被捕
但得到缓刑五年  此后不曾再犯罪
1989年  亨利与凯伦在婚后25年正式离婚
保罗·西席罗因呼吸道问题1988年死于监狱  享年73岁
吉米·康威目前仍在纽约州监狱以谋杀的罪名服刑
他必须等到2004年  他78岁时才能获得假释